<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Student>



<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-124</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>SECURE AND ADAPTIVE VIDEO CONFERENCING</Project_Name>
	<Domain>NETWORKING</Domain>
	<Abstract>We are developing a secure and adaptive video conferencing system, which allows multiple users to exchange their real time audio and video streams in a secure manner. The video streams are compressed using the software codec. The video is divided into frames and then stored as layers. The user will get these ‘frames’ as per the bandwidth availability. After compression, both audio and video streams are encrypted and then transmitted over the network using application layer multicast. Each node in the network may have one or more users. All the users will get the data no matter what is the bandwidth of their connection, although at the cost of a little quality. If the bandwidth of the user changes or connection becomes faster, he would get it accordingly, which makes it adaptive. Due to the lower bandwidth of any particular user, others won’t be affected. The technique used for this adaptive data exchange is layered video encoding. This will be applicable to all senders and receivers, hence making                    it a many-to-many network. We are doing all the processing like compression, decompression, encryption, decryption in software so no extra hardware is required. Encryption will help us keep the communication secure.</Abstract>
</Project>

<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-137</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>RESOURCE MONITORING AND EVENT NOTIFICATION USING JMX</Project_Name>
	<Domain>NETWORKING</Domain>
	<Abstract>Our aim is to develop a Resource Monitoring and Event Notification system that enables us to monitor critical system resources such as processor , disk , memory usage and send user notifications . Main aim of the system is to detect and send user notifications through e-mail for : 1.Detect low memory 2.Enable / disable GC  3.Detect deadlocks 4.Access OS resources The Java Management Extensions (JMX)  defines a Java package that provides a management architecture and API set that will allow any Java technology–based or accessible resource to be manageable.By using JMX, you can manage Java technology resources. 
                   JMX is so easy to use and is so suited for the Java development paradigm that it is possible to make an application manageable in three to five lines of code.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-206</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>ROUTE RESERVATION IN AD HOC WIRELESS NETWORKS</Project_Name>
	<Domain>NETWORKING</Domain>
	<Abstract>The research work we will illustrate here will basically focus on the different techniques used for communication in wireless networks. when route reservation-based (RB) communication can yield better delay performance than non-reservation-based (NRB) communication in ad hoc wireless networks. In addition to posing this fundamental question, the requirements (in terms of route discovery, medium access control (MAC) protocol, and pipelining, etc.) for making RB switching superior to NRB switching are also identified. A novel analytical framework is developed and the network performance under both RB and NRB schemes is quantified. It is shown that if the aforementioned requirements are met, then RB schemes can indeed yield better delay performance than NRB schemes. This advantage, however, comes at the expense</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-232</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>LAN CACHE USING BROWSER INDEX</Project_Name>
	<Domain>NETWORKING</Domain>
	<Abstract>When a web page is requested it is searched locally in the cache if it is available in local cache then it is retrieved from local cache. Otherwise, the request is transferred to proxy server if it contains the requested object then it is forwarded to client. If it doesn’t content the requested page the global search of the page is done through DNS. LAN Cache system allows efficient use of internet and increases the speed of fetching a particular page by improving hit ratio of cache system. This concept discusses web caching and how this can be improved using a p2p system that interconnects the browser cache of each client with the cache of the web proxy so that clients and proxy share their cache contents. In this way hit ratio is improved within the whole system and redundant replication is avoided. The proposed architecture presented in the concept is that the proxy keeps track of client cache contents. So when there is a cache miss, the requested document is searched in other client caches. If there is a hit, then the document is forwarded to the client who made the request and stored in the appropriate cache in order to reduce document duplication. Here concept is to maintain a browser index file which will contain the information about each data objects available in browser cache. For each miss browser index file will be searched for that data object. So bandwidth will be saved and speed will increase.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-123</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>USB OVER IP</Project_Name>
	<Domain>NETWORK AND INFORMATION SYSTEM SECURITY</Domain>
	<Abstract>As personal computing becomes more popular and affordable, the availability of peripheral devices is also increasing rapidly. However, these peripheral devices can usually only be connected to a single machine at time. The ability to share peripheral devices between computers without any modification of existing computing environments is, consequently, a highly desirable goal, as it improves the efficiency and usability of such devices. Existing device sharing technologies in the pervasive computing area are not sufficient for peripheral devices designed for personal computers, because these technologies do not provide the degree of network transparency necessary for both applications and device drivers. Again if the security issue is taken under consideration, this conversation is not secured over the Internet. So, its basic need is that the data which flows between the two peers should be encrypted such that even though an intruder catches the data he could not make anything out of it.  In this paper, we propose USB/IP WITH SECURE COMMUNICATION as a peripheral bus extension over an Internet Protocol (IP) network. This novel device sharing approach is based on the sophisticated peripheral interfaces that are supported in most modern operating systems. Using a virtual peripheral bus driver, users can share a diverse range of devices over networks without any modification in existing operating systems and applications. All types of USB’s are supportable viz. isochronous, block, control, and interrupt. We will be applying security using cryptographic algorithms for provision of encryption/decryption module viz. AES algorithm and Blowfish algorithm. User will be given a choice of which algorithm is to be used for data transfer.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-205</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>BIOMETRIC FOLDER LOCKING SYSTEM USING FUZZY VAULT FOR FINGERPRINTS</Project_Name>
	<Domain>NETWORK AND INFORMATION SYSTEM SECURITY</Domain>
	<Abstract>Traditional cryptographic commitment needs exact data i.e. unique decryption key. Traditional systems have a very high proven security but they suffer from the key management problem. Also these systems require keys to be very long and random for higher security e.g. 128 bits which makes it impossible for users to memorize the keys. Most of the authentication mechanism use passwords to release the correct decrypting key, but these mechanisms are unable to provide non-repudiation.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-230</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>A WEB BASED DASHBOARD FOR SECURITY ASSESSMENT</Project_Name>
	<Domain>NETWORK AND INFORMATION SYSTEM SECURITY</Domain>
	<Abstract>The use of web applications by industries in all fields of study is increasing by the day. These Web 2.0 applications are used for almost all the purposes ranging from simple informational web sites to complex e-commerce applications. Due to their popularity, it becomes a huge pool of target for attackers. Any loophole in the design of these applications makes them more vulnerable against attackers. To safeguard against the vulnerabilities, various tools such as Ratproxy, Nessus, Nmap, Paros, etc are famous among web application designers. Though most of these tools report threats for similar vulnerabilities the constraints here are: Tools are compatible to only particular OS, no GUI for some tools, their reporting formats are different, etc. The ‘Web Based Dashboard for Security Assessment’ is a common dashboard for all such tools. Users can select any of the provided tools to scan their applications. The Dashboard is designed as a framework which enables plug-in facility to add a new tool to the Dashboard with minimal efforts. It helps to bring various Web Application Scanners under one common abstracted interface and the comprehensive and uniform reports make it easier for the developer to build secure applications by easily identifying the vulnerabilities existing in the application. This paper thus presents an idea for a tool which is first of its kind and with concentrated efforts can turn out to be an important commercial product in the field of Information Security.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-136</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>GSM BASED POSITIONING FOR LOCATION BASED SERVICES</Project_Name>
	<Domain>WIRELESS AND MOBILE COMMUNICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>In today’s world, it has become imperative to know one’s position geographically. This will help to get information and services that are available locally. This project aims at designing an application that will enable the user to get his/her location and using this the user will also be able to use various location based offers and reminders. The user will be able to use these services without GPS. GSM Technology will be used to get the various cell-parameters and using these parameters, the location will be found. The benefit of using GSM technology is that it can be used indoors where GPS doesn’t work. Also, GPS phones are expensive and battery consuming. The application will be developed for Nokia Symbian60 Series.  It will make use of the location of the user to provide location based offers and reminders. The project aims to locate the position of the user with an accuracy of 200 meters.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-207</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>SELF-CARE CLIENT</Project_Name>
	<Domain>WIRELESS AND MOBILE COMMUNICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Mobile Users are provided with various Value Added Services (VAS) such as GPRS, Hello Tunes and other Customer-care services like balance-checking. At present, access to these services and user account is confusing and often time-consuming. Subscription to a particular service becomes an issue since each service has a separate activation number and the customer must memorize the number of the service he is interested in. Another problem is that the notification of call duration and charge can be verified only once, i.e. just after the call has been completed - thus leaving no means for a customer to refer to it again. As for customer-care websites, one needs to go through a number of links to get the desired information. The customer follows a different path for every service he wishes to subscribe to. Even after this, he must manually request for the specific service. With our application, individual users can access their account information as well as use value-added services with the click of a button. The Self-care Client is a mobile application that allows users universal easy access to self-manage their account directly from a mobile device. It proves to be an easier alternative as it can be used anywhere, anytime without any hardware except a mobile. Apart from providing services like balance checking, checking of account information, call records and activation or deactivation of services, this application also provides a facility for registering complaints and checking the status using a unique id.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-210</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>PAIR-WISE TIME SYNCHRONISATION IN WIRELESS SENSOR NETWORK</Project_Name>
	<Domain>WIRELESS AND MOBILE COMMUNICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Recent advances in miniaturization and low-cost , low-power design have led to active research in large-scale networks of small, wireless, low-power sensors. In a typical Wireless Sensor Network (WSN) application, a WSN is scattered in a region where it is meant to collect data through its sensor nodes. Specific applications include battlefield surveillance, object tracking, nuclear reactor control, fire detection, home automation, habitat monitoring, vehicle detection, etc .Time synchronization is a critical piece of infrastructure in any of these WSN because of its extensive use of time stamping. A common view of physical time is the basic requirement for nodes to reason about events that occur in the physical world. We consider global time synchronization protocol in which nodes synchronize their clocks to a reference master clock (say, UTC provided by the GPS). However, while the clock accuracy and precision requirements are often stricter in sensor networks, energy and channel constraints limit the resources available to meet these goals. For various reasons it is desirable that the number of time-synchronizing nodes are minimum and optimally placed. Modeling Sensor Network as a graph with sensor nodes as vertices and edges as the communication link, we provide solution for optimal placement of time-synchronizing nodes in multi-hop WSN.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-214</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>LOST MOBILE TRACKING SYSTEM</Project_Name>
	<Domain>WIRELESS AND MOBILE COMMUNICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>When an owner loses a mobile phone, the loss is usually reported to the cellular service provider, who will then disable the phone number associated with the Subscriber Identity Module (SIM). This action ensures that anyone who picks up the lost mobile phone (for convenience, we shall label such people “thieves”) is unable to “freeload” on owner’s call time. However, it does not prevent the thief from using the phone with another SIM nor to extract the owner’s personal information from the phone. Lost Mobile Tracking System is a comprehensive and intelligible tool proven to significantly reduce the theft and maintain the system integrity. It assists the mobile owner to trace the missing mobile through an innovative system. It ensures sensitive owners assets and personal information. The proposed system detects the removal of SIM card and checks whether it’s the original one, or else it sends message to the preconfigured numbers with the location details of whereabouts of the place where the mobile is recently situated. Location details include the cellid which is the unique number of a GSM cell for a given operator, mnc(mobile network code), mcc(mobile country code).In case of lost mobile, whenever the LOCK sms is received, it automatically backups the phone data and uploads it on web server. Along with that it locks the phone so that the thief cannot further use it.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-228</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>INTEGRATION OF CALENDARS WITH PROFILES IN CELL PHONES</Project_Name>
	<Domain>WIRELESS AND MOBILE COMMUNICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>This project is about integrating the calendars with profiles in cell phones. The main objective of the project is to ease the usage of cell phones. Reduction of manual intervention, while handling the cell phones will be achieved. Application present at high range cell phones will be implemented in low range cell phones. The user has an overhead in his busy schedule to always remember and change the profile when he changes his place or moves from one event to another. By chance if he forgets to change the profile, he may face the problem of missing some important calls or disturbance of some unimportant calls. In case of disturbing calls user may just reject the call without giving the caller any idea about why the call has been rejected. The idea of the project is to achieve the objective of automatic changing of profiles as per the schedule given by the user in calendars in their cell phones. In addition it will automatically block the call which the user feels are not important. Software will also send some kind of notification to the caller like it will send message or a dialer tone may be set, specifying what the user is actually doing. For developing the project J2ME technology will be used. Supporting development toolkits will be SDK S60 version 2 FP3, Eclipse (eclipse-java-galileo).</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-246</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>DEVELOPMENT OF AGENT-BASED, PEER-TO-PEER MOBILE APPLICATION AND AN APPLICATION FOR REMOTE FILE SEARCH OPERATION BETWEEN TWO DEVICES</Project_Name>
	<Domain>WIRELESS AND MOBILE COMMUNICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Mobile Search is becoming increasingly important for mobile users as mobile devices are more widely used. Mobile search differs from standard PC-based search in a number of ways: (1) the user interfaces and I/O are limited by screen real estate and tiny key pads are tiny, (2) increased local search due to mobility. These limitations result in more navigational queries in the mobile search. In this we will have two devices and we will be able to search from one device the contents of other device. We describe how to develop peer-to-peer and social applications for the ANDROID SDK, the new mobile platform delivered by Google within the Open Handset Alliance at November 2007. In particular we focus on using JADE, a popular open source framework that facilitates the development of interoperable intelligent multi-agent systems. In our opinion JADE, thanks to the expressiveness of its communication model, brings strong added value to ANDROID SDK platform in the development of innovative applications based on social models and peer-to-peer paradigm.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-304</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>SIMULATION OF DYNAMIC CHANNEL ALLOCATION ALGORITHM FOR CELLULAR MOBILE COMMUNICATION</Project_Name>
	<Domain>WIRELESS AND MOBILE COMMUNICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>In the world of communications, bandwidth is priceless. The rapid evolution of cellular technology and the increasing subscriber demand for advanced mobile services has lead the industry to develop more efficient mobile network structures. This drives the research for new methodologies in the design of cellular networks and services. But, the frequency spectrum is a rare commodity and a costly one too. Hence we need efficient resource allocation algorithms to make an economical usage of it and incorporate a larger number of subscribers. This in turn can be beneficiary to both the mobile network service providers as well as the subscribers. There are various dynamic channel algorithms designed for channel allocation in mobile communication, the limitation being, most algorithms concentrate on some parameters, others are traded-off. Hence, we plan to design an algorithm that optimizes most of the parameters under consideration. In this project, initially we emphasized on various algorithms that have already been designed. We studied each of these algorithms, their advantages and trade-offs. We are designing a new algorithm for dynamic channel assignment in cellular mobile systems so as to improve channel usage efficiency in GSM mobile communication. The parameters and the working of the algorithm will be worked upon as per the algorithms already been studied. This algorithm will not only carry out the effective allocation of the spectrum, but also ensure that maximum number of subscribers are serviced. Also taken into account is the blocking probability, call clarity and network resources utilized.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-307</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>TO DESIGN AN ALGORITHM WHICH WILL USE AVAILABLE RESOURCES EFFICIENTLY, PROVIDING BETTER QOS. REDUCING CALL DROPPING RATE AND MAINTAINING CALL BLOCKING PROBABILITY TO LOW LEVEL</Project_Name>
	<Domain>WIRELESS AND MOBILE COMMUNICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>For a cellular system the major resources available are:1. Bandwidth  2. Power Out of which bandwidth is a major issue of concern. Because the spectrum allocated for cellular communication is limited. High-speed cellular networks working today are expected to support multimedia applications, which require QoS provisions. Since frequency spectrum is the most expensive resource in wireless networks, it is a challenge to support QoS usingLinearLayout limited frequency spectrum. In the literature, two orthogonal approaches are used to address the bandwidth utilization issue and the QoS provision issue; that is, channel allocation schemes have been proposed to improve bandwidth efficiency, whereas handoff management schemes, based on bandwidth reservation, have been proposed to guarantee a low connection dropping rate. Genetic algorithms are used for optimisation. Genetic algorithms are search algorithms based on the mechanics of natural selection and natural genetics. GAS  exploit the idea of the survival of the fittest and an interbreeding population to create a novel and innovative search strategy  We have proposed a Genetic Algorithm for HANDOFF MANAGEMENT which results in reducing call dropping rate of handoff calls while maintaining call blocking probability of newly arrived calls to a low level i.e to provide better QoS(Quality of Service).</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-141</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>AUTO MONITORING SYSTEM</Project_Name>
	<Domain>INTELLIGENT SYSTEMS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Automatic number plate recognition system is a special set of hardware and software components that processes an input graphical signal like static pictures or video sequences, and recognizes license plate characters from it. Alternative to this solution is a software detection of an incoming vehicle, signal.Image processor recognizes static snapshots captured by the camera, and returns a text representation of the detected license plate. ANPR units can have own dedicated image processors (all-in-one solution), or they can send captured data to a central processing unit for further processing (generic ANPR). The image processor is running on special recognition software.Quality of captured snapshots should be good.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-204</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>COMPARISON OF HEURISTIC ALGORITHMS FOR GRAPH PATIONNING TO OPTIMIZE SEARCHING</Project_Name>
	<Domain>INTELLIGENT SYSTEMS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Problem arises in searching whole graph due to memory limitations of workstations and information processing ability. This is prohibitively expensive to load representation of graph into memory. Thus it motivates us to use automated techniques to partition the graph into smaller pieces which are self sufficient in which queries will tend to be satisfied with nodes from single portion of partition. Hence there is a need for dividing graphs into individually loadable portions, with the objective of minimizing the number of partitions that must be loaded for simple queries.For graph partitioning various heuristic approaches such as Kernighan-Lin, fiduccia   heuristic can be used to speed up the graph searches. The efficiency of these algorithms will be compared by replacing existing searching technique by MLL.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-308</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>PERFOMANCE ANALYSIS OF HANDWRITTEN DEVNAGRI CHARACTERS USING ANN</Project_Name>
	<Domain>INTELLIGENT SYSTEMS</Domain>
	<Abstract>This work deals with the recognition of Devnagari characters using statistical approach. Several methods for recognizing Latin, Chinese, Arabic characters have been proposed, while the recognition of Devnagari characters has been relatively sparse. The techniques which are used for classifying the characters in other languages cannot be applied for the recognition of Devnagari characters because of the difference in structure of this language; therefore, the recognition rate of Devnagari characters is lower than that of the disconnected characters, such  as English. The recognition and processing of handwritten characters is largely motivated by desire to improve man and machine communication. The important phase of OCR i.e. feature extraction is used in this work. The application of moments as a feature extractor provides a method for describing the properties of an object in terms of its area, position, orientation, and other precisely defined parameters.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-105</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>AUTO MONITORING SYSTEM</Project_Name>
	<Domain>USER APPLICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Automatic number plate recognition system is a special set of hardware and software components that processes an input graphical signal like static pictures or video sequences, and recognizes license plate characters from it. Alternative to this solution is a software detection of an incoming vehicle, signal.Image processor recognizes static snapshots captured by the camera, and returns a text representation of the detected license plate. ANPR units can have own dedicated image processors (all-in-one solution), or they can send captured data to a central processing unit for further processing (generic ANPR). The image processor is running on special recognition software.Quality of captured snapshots should be good.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-117</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>A WEB BASED CONSOLE APPLICATION TO MANAGE THE CONFIGURATION OF OMSD PRODUCTION SETUP</Project_Name>
	<Domain>USER APPLICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>OMSD (Order Management System Direct) is STS product which provides connectivity with all exchanges and ECNs for order routing and receiving executions. Today there are almost 10 complexes where more than 25 connections on each complex connection to external systems for order routing. Each complex represent set processes that represent a solution for a firm. To manage these connections; production support and operation team manages configuration files manually. OMSD is expected to progress and have many more connections and additional complexes in production. That would require a controlled and centralized process to manage these connections. We present, a user friendly interactive intranet application that will read and parse current configuration files and represent them in graphical manner. This application allows user to add/edit and delete configuration files.It validates all edits by user and  implements those in form of configuration files.This project comes up with a handy tool for viewing the status of  different processes and threads in an Order Management System. In case, if a process is stuck at some point in the network, it becomes very easy to detect various parameters regarding exactly what and where the problem has occurred from the GUI designed.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-121</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>OMNI-DESK</Project_Name>
	<Domain>USER APPLICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Often it happens that we need to access a computer from a remote place where computer network is not available. For example, you just want to monitor a process going on your computer when you are on drive. You need to see the desktop and operate it for that purpose. As a solution to this common problem, we have come up with an idea to build an application for an ANDROID phone in which we communicate with the remote computer under the RDP (Remote Desktop Protocol). RDP enables us to display the desktop of remote computer by sending the drawing instruction or the bitmap images from that computer. These instructions can be used to draw the desktop using the OpenGL library. The features of the phone such as touch sense and keyboard can be used to operate the desktop.RDP is a proprietary protocol of Windows, so only the Windows OSs (versions after Windows 2000) uses it for communication. So, scope of our project is limited to Windows OSs. In future enhancements we can easily accommodate VNC (Virtual Network Computing ) for UNIX platforms.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-138</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>ONLINE NATIONAL POLLING</Project_Name>
	<Domain>USER APPLICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>We live in a democracy and voting is one of our fundamental duties as responsible citizens of the country, but nowhere around the country a 100% people come to vote during the elections in their constituency There are several reasons responsible for it. To curb down the effect of such factors, we hereby propose a project whose basic idea is to conduct national polls online through the internet.Keeping in mind the several reasons that are responsible for less number of people casting a vote and to improve the state of democracy in the country Online Polling System can be thought as a solution, in conjunction with the ongoing current manual voting system.The application that is developed will enable users to use:- 1. Casting Vote by citizens 2.Profile Management by the participating candidates.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-209</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>VIRTUALIZATION POLICY MANAGEMENT</Project_Name>
	<Domain>USER APPLICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Organizations, today, are using advanced dynamic datacenters empowered by virtualization technology to manage their resources. Agile and scalable nature of this virtual infrastructure is bringing new management challenges for the datacenters. Normally organizations employ more than one vendor in their datacenters. Thus organizations are faced with the cumbersome task of monitoring all the virtualization technologies separately. Organizations need a datacenter infrastructure in place that is manageable, scalable, and reliable, giving the organization the flexibility it needs to seamlessly allocate, monitor, and manage resources.One of the solutions to address this problem is to manage these datacenters by enforcing a set of policies. These set of policies will continuously monitor all the virtual machines and the virtual infrastructure to ensure proper resource utilization and management. Our project focuses on framing a vendor neutral policy engine that is capable of managing datacenter policies for virtual infrastructure and enforces them by taking appropriate action. The policy engine would also be useful to keep a track of all the virtual machines and the resources used by them. This is essential to measure the resource usage of the organization and maintain the infrastructure costs of the organization. The policy engine will work in accordance with these communication centers using well defined APIs and SDKs of different virtualization vendors. Our solution also provides analysis of various Virtual assets such as storage and CPU usage for every virtual machine. This information helps the datacenter to use its resources efficiently.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-216</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>USER FRIENDLY XEN VIRTUAL MACHINE MANAGER</Project_Name>
	<Domain>USER APPLICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Xen is a virtual-machine monitor for x86, x86-64, Itanium and PowerPC 970 architectures. It allows several guest operating systems to execute on the same computer hardware concurrently. A Xen system is structured with the Xen hypervisor as the lowest and most privileged layer. Above this layer are one or more guest operating systems, which the hypervisor schedules across the physical CPUs.[5].The "Virtual Machine Manager" application is a desktop user interface for managing virtual machines. It presents a summary view of running domains, their live performance and resource utilization statistics. The detailed view graphs performance and utilization over time. Wizards enable the creation of new domains, and configuration and adjustment of existing domains. For eg: Citrix’s Xencenter.But this VMMs cannot be used online and thus are limited to only enterprises. Our application will be the first to provide the features of VMM online. VMMs can be created, managed and configured using this Web service. Thus our project intended to provide VMM as a web service. We’ll be using Django web framework for this purpose which comes embedded with sqlite3 database support and apache server. Python is used as a programming language.  Django 1.1.1 provides support for python 2.6.4</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-217</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>TO DEVELOP A TECHNOLOGY THAT WILL HELP USERS WITH UNKNOWN DOCUMENTS OR UNKNOWN EXTENSIONS, ALSO PROVIDE A OPTION FOR CONVERTING A FILE FROM ONE UNKNOWN EXTENSION TO KNOWN EXTENSION</Project_Name>
	<Domain>USER APPLICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Applications are growing in size day by day. These applications tend to eat up a lot of disk space. When we need to use any new software, installation of that software is required. Installation is a time-consuming process and it also takes lot of disk space. Given the complexity of modern applications, there are many functions or options available in applications which are never or seldom used. But even if user wants to use any new software he has to keep the set-up file of that particular software and has to install the whole software which is time consuming and ridiculous task.In this project we have removed all these drawbacks like user need not suppose to set-up file and installation of any new software if he wants to make use of it. It will be always an effective option for any user to able to directly run the software of his choice.This project will provide a user with a new way to interact with files. The basic idea behind developing a project is to provide a user utility when he needs some application but not having a set-up file of that particular application. This system will also provide identification of files and corresponding utilities for the user who are not familiar with particular file type.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-220</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>EXECUTABLE AND LINKABLE</Project_Name>
	<Domain>USER APPLICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Created by the assembler and link editors, ELF object files are binary representations of programs intended to execute directly on a processor. The File contains headers of the files, sections and segments. The sections hold all the data in the file needed for execution. The bulk of information stored in the sections is debug information which is not at all needed for execution. So the space used is wasted in information which is worth nothing.       This motivated us to develop such a utility which optimizes the ELF in size, removing the unused information. This utility can prove itself very useful for embedded applications where the memory space costs a lot. The utility can also be used for ELFs run-able on ARM Family of advanced microprocessors.Portable consumer applications are becoming more sophisticated with each new generation. User expectations are for better user interfaces, faster graphics, and larger screens to support a broader range of applications, such as video phones, games, news services, and movies. Typical design requirements then include: better operating system support, and support for streaming multimedia applications. At the same time, achieving lowest memory requirements, low product cost, and low power, remain critical factors in ensuring that adoption of high-end portable and wireless appliances becomes ‘mainstream’.To achieve these requirements, our utility can be used as powerful tool for optimization in the range of 75–85%. The optimization in the executable file is indirectly proportional to the memory space utilization. Thus we can increase the utilization by optimizing the size of the executables.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-222</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>CLOUDME:A PLATFORM INDEPENDENT CLOUD AWARE APPLICATION MANAGEMENT TOOL</Project_Name>
	<Domain>USER APPLICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>We propose to build a platform independent cloud aware application management software that is efficient, transparent and secure to launch and access applications across different operating system environments, residing in different terminals over a network of cloud servers. The application eradicates the need of heavy weight software like X server programs at the display machine, complex connection establishments, and a plenteous of other credentials, burdening the end user. Such a system is of a higher relevance in a cloud computing scenario as today the need of system scalability in order to match the application requirement is of great importance. The remotely running applications are presented in such a manner that allows users to switch seamlessly amongst different programs and having the user experience a whole new dimension to cloud computing. The immense development in platform interoperability has brought about a wide range of tools and methods to have Unix applications run on local windows desktop and vice versa, like virtualization, remote desktop terminals, secure shell. To invoke a remote application one definitely needs to go through a variety of steps, say setting up the connection in secure shell or logging to the remote desktop. All such dependency limitations are wiped away by using the VNC (Virtual Network Computing). A VNC system is a thin client reducing the amount of state maintained at the user’s terminal. By using this striking feature of VNC we aim to take the remote desktop to the next level As cloud offerings such as SAAS (Software as a Service) and IAAS (Infrastructure as a Service) are getting main stream and closer to the less sophisticated masses, we propose to build a tool that combines processing power across the globe.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-223</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>REPORTS ON YOUR FINGURES</Project_Name>
	<Domain>USER APPLICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>In the last few years, SMS (Short Message Service) has made a big impact on the way we communicate. Instead of communicating over the phone using voice, more and more people are turning to use SMS for communication. The sending of the attendance, meeting letter to parents by post costs much more than sending SMS and it is slower process than sending SMS also sometime there is possibility of letter missing, so SMS will be the better option. Also it will make system paperless and save environment from global warming.We are Developing an Application which has got inbound as well as outbound interfaces. The outbound interface sends monthly attendance of students, University Results, Parent’s Meet Notice and Other Notices to Parent’s as well as Student’s Mobile Phone. The Application also Receives Messages Sent by Parent and directs them to Student’s Class Coordinator’s Mobile.The Application facilitates to update the Mobile number of Parent on Parent’s Request and also on student’s request. The Application generates Delivery Report hence undelivered Messages are Redelivered after particular time automatically and after three attempts if undelivered then generates it’s Printout to send by post. The Front End used in this Project is JSP and Back End is SQL. The Central Server is established by using Apache Tomcat Server and MySQL works as database server. GSM modem is used for sending message from central server. Administrator maintain’s the central server.This Software makes the overall process Transparent and quick. </Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-227</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>OFFLINE VIRTUAL MACHINE MANAGER</Project_Name>
	<Domain>USER APPLICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>A virtual machines(VM) existence on disk is just a group of files. These files represent  configuration information(CPU, Memory, etc) and disk. Disk file contains OS and data associated to the VM. Considering the case that there are virtual machines scattered over network and we need to find the details of all the machines then the problem is that for fetching installation and configuration details, we need to switch on each and every virtual disc every time. If all these virtual machines are on the same host OS then it would take less time. But if these are located on network then it is tedious and time consuming to locate, switch on and then fetch the details. Also installation of softwares on virtual machines is time consuming. Considering the above scenario we propose to design a tool that will gather the inventory details of Virtual Machine in its offline mode, index the details fetched from the VM for easy access to administrators and also provide a facility to install software packages in off-peak hours. Using this tool we can read the disk files of the VM, and extract the inventory details of guest OS in the offline mode of the VM. The inventory details provide information about installed OS and installed application. We also index the information of the available VMs and provide administrator with an efficient tool for searching a required VM which suites particular task.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-240</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>STEGO_VOIP</Project_Name>
	<Domain>USER APPLICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>The real-time text hiding is to hide the secret text into a cover speech in real-time communication systems. By hiding one secret text into the cover speech, we can get a stego-speech, which sounds meaningful and indistinguishable from the original cover speech. Therefore, even if the Hackers/Crackers catch the audio packets on Network, they would not notice that there is some secret text hidden inside it. In this paper, we propose a scheme for text hiding in a real-time communication system such as voice over Internet Protocol (VoIP).Suppose Sender  wants to send confidential Data like a message “secret” to Reciever over the Internet.  Then using traditional Crypto Technique, it will encrypt “secret” message with a key and send this encrypted along with the key to Comp2.  Comp2 will decrypt it with a KEY.  Now there are many problems associated with this approach, like if the Hacker/Cracker intercepts the Packets and damages it or is able to hack the Comp1’s key or impersonate Comp2.  A new approach in Network Data hiding is to hide the Secret Text and series of characters of “secret” in actual voice packet while keeping the application of the system intact. Any malicious user who would  try to intercept this data would find this data as important as original VOIP data.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-244</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>HOME SECURITY AND SURVEILLANCE SYSTEM (HAWK EYE)</Project_Name>
	<Domain>USER APPLICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>With security system providers on the prowl for new ways to expand business and home control companies seeking non-traditional channels of distribution. According  to the market research report the need of security personnel at home or installation of CCTV is decreasing day by day and market in the need of the urgent requirements for high-tech, self controlled security installation. A secure physical asset guarantees peace of mind but in this age where everything is at premium this peace of mind doesn’t come cheap. CCTV itself has limitations like :  1.High initial investments. 2.Alarm facilities not included. 3.In ability of CCTV camera to generate noise free images real-time. 4.Constant monitoring required of critical security areas. We have addressed the above needs, not currently met, by developing hawkeye, a comprehensible and flexible security framework and application. The Project aims at providing a java library for snapshot generation , live video recording and streaming over internet. Along with a J2ME application which allows remote viewing of live feed Via GPRS/3G. Its manifest utility in commercial and industry use makes it an important application. It also has the advantage of being portable, cheap, easy to configure. Hawkeye’s mobile module can be used on any mobile  which is java enabled and has GPRS or 3G connectivity, thus its use is not restricted to high end phones .Also the webcams used provide a cheap alternatives to CCTV and coupled with image filtration algorithms we can get clear images to support as evidence along with videos.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-245</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>WEBTOP</Project_Name>
	<Domain>USER APPLICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>A web desktop or webtop is a desktop environment embedded in a web browser or similar client application. A webtop integrates web applications, web services, client-server applications, application servers, and applications on the local client into a desktop environment using the desktop metaphor. Web desktops provide an environment similar to that of Windows, Mac, or a graphical user interface on Unix and Linux systems. It is a virtual desktop running in a web browser. In a webtop the applications, data, files, configuration, settings, and access privileges reside remotely over the network. Much of the computing takes place remotely. The browser is primarily used for display and input purposes. The terms "web desktop" and "webtop" are distinct from web operating system, a network operating system such as TinyOS or distributed operating system such as Inferno. In popular use, web desktops are sometimes referred to incorrectly as web operating systems or simply WebOS. Purpose:-This is to clarify the requirements to build a Webdesktop . It can be used by thin clients, which cannot afford the costly software application tools available in market. Webtop is used for accessing your own desktop applications so it is user – friendly and easily maintained.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-101</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>REDESIGN OF UNSORTED BLOCK IMAGES (UBI) METADATA LAYOUT FOR FASTER MOUNT</Project_Name>
	<Domain>SYSTEM APPLICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>The project aims at optimizing the mount time of raw flash devices that use Unsorted Block Images (UBI) as the flash interface layer. It does so by redesigning the metadata lay-out on the device. Using the proposed design, the mount time is reduced by a factor of around 32-128 times of the current mount time, depending on the flash parameters.  Currently, the metadata of the flash device is distributed over the entire device. At mount time, the entire device has to be linearly scanned to construct the flash metadata tables in RAM. Thus, the mount time is directly proportional to size of the flash device. This high mount time deters the use of UBI, in netbooks and plug computers, in which size of raw flash is significantly large.In the proposed design, all the metadata of the flash device is stored in a group of blocks on the device.  Constructing the metadata tables requires reading only these few blocks (less than 1% of the total number of blocks on the device). However, the wear-leveling operation is required to be performed on these blocks, to ensure uniform use of flash. Because of this, at mount time, there is no fixed location on the device at which the metadata will be present. The design addresses the above constraint and maintains metadata consistency inspite of conditions like power failures or unclean unmount, with minimal processing overheads. Thus, the project makes it feasible to use UBI with large raw flash memory.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-102</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>TO DESIGN A SCHEDULING SCHEME SO AS TO BRING ABOUT PERFORMANCE ISOLATION AND TO ACCOMMODATE THE DIVERSE AND UNPREDICTABLE WORKLOADS OF DIFFERENT VMS TO BRING ABOUT SCHEDULING FAIRNESS BETWEEN CPU BOUND AND I/O BOUND TASKS IN GUEST VIRTUAL MACHINES</Project_Name>
	<Domain>SYSTEM APPLICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>To enhance the I/O responsiveness, Utopia develops an inference mechanism to infer whether a task is I/O bound. This is done by monitoring the context switches. The frequency of change of the CR3 register is used to determine if a task is I/O bound or not. If a task is inferred to be I/O bound, then, I/O requests sent by such tasks are flagged. When a flagged I/O request completes, the priority of the domain which sent the request is boosted and it pre-empts the currently executing domain. Hence, the I/O responsiveness is enhanced. Once the I/O bound task completes then domain is pre-empted so that the overall fairness is not compromised.To enforce performance isolation Utopia employs a scheme similar to the existing credit system. IDD-credits are assigned to each domain to limit the amount of work that it can delegate to the IDD. For network I/O, the number of packets sent and received by each domain, packect_count(Domi) as well as the IDD, packet_count(IDD) are monitored. Then, the ratio packet_count(Domi) packet_count(IDD) is used to charge the credits to each domain, which is the fraction of total credits spent  by IDD in processing requests from all the domains. If a domain over-utilizes the IDD, it will run out of IDD-credits. Subsequent network I/O from such a domain will be blocked, until it acquires IDD-credits, which are allocated per accounting period.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-106</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>CONDITIONAL BRANCHING OPTIMIZATION FOR RUN-TIME PARALLELIZATION IN GCC</Project_Name>
	<Domain>SYSTEM APPLICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>As the meteoric rise in multi-core technology continues, the sequential model of program execution (traditional von Neumann model) falls short to provide sustained performance improvements owing to under-utilization of available parallel resources by the sequentially executing programs, obeying Moore’s law. Current trends in computing point towards platforms seeking performance improvements through various degrees of parallelism, with coarse-grained parallelism features becoming commonplace. Yet, there still remain number of existing programs which continue to pose considerable speed deficiency in execution. Several parallelization techniques and algorithms have been proposed in the past to harness mid-grain level parallelism, which are continuously added to existing compilers like GCC. The techniques, broadly categorized as static time and run time (such as loop tiling, loop distribution, speculative parallelization etc) focus chiefly on loop optimization since loops are essentially the programming constructs to do tasks serially. We propose to perform our optimizations in GCC based on the runtime technique of speculative parallelization focusing mainly on conditional branching statements and simple iterative loops. Although GCC boasts of number of loop optimizations, it lacks conditional branching optimizations especially meant for parallelization. The conditional branching statements, on average, amount for 50% of any non-trivial program. Moreover, the intermediate representation (Gimple) of GCC which is useful for optimization consists of IF-ELSE-GOTO constructs only. Hence, conditional branching statement optimizations can have profound speed-up. Thus, we propose a way in which conditional branching construct can be parallelized speculatively at run-time and improve the speed-up and the utilization of multiple (two) cores.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-109</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>H-CACHE: HYPERVISOR BASED CACHE</Project_Name>
	<Domain>SYSTEM APPLICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Managing a fixed amount of memory (RAM) optimally is a long-solved problem in the Linux kernel. Managing RAM optimally in a virtual environment, however, is still a challenging problem because: (1) each guest kernel focuses solely on optimizing its entire fixed RAM allocation oblivious to the needs of other guests, and (2) very little information is exposed to the virtual machine manager (VMM) to enable it to decide if one guest needs RAM more than another guest. Mechanisms such as ballooning and hot-plug memory allow RAM to be taken from a selfish guest and given to a needy guest, but these have significant known issues and, in any case, don’t solve the hard problem: Which guests are selfish and which are needy? IBM’s Collaborative Memory Management attempts to collect information from each guest and provide it to the VMM, but was deemed far too complex and attempts to upstream it have been mostly stymied. Hypervisor-based cache – or “Hcache” – is an approach to optimize RAM utilization in a virtual environment. Hcache can be implemented not using physical storage media, but instead with “spare” physical memory in the hypervisor of a virtualized system. Hcache can be accessed.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-139</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>EXTRACTING ACTIONABLE KNOWLEDGE FROM DECISION TREE FOR CRM</Project_Name>
	<Domain>SYSTEM APPLICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Most data mining algorithms and tools stop at discovered customer models, producing distribution information on customer profiles. Such techniques, when applied to industrial problems such as customer relationship management (CRM), are useful in pointing out customers who are likely attritors and customers who are loyal, but they require human experts to post process the discovered knowledge manually. Most of the post processing techniques have been limited to producing visualization results and interestingness ranking, but they do not directly suggest actions that would lead to an increase in the objective function such as profit. In this paper, we present novel algorithms that suggest actions to change customers from an undesired status (such as attritors) to a desired one (such as loyal) while maximizing an objective function: the expected net profit. These algorithms can discover cost effective actions to transform customers from undesirable classes to desirable ones. The approach we take integrates data mining and decision making tightly by formulating the decision making problems directly on top of the data mining results in a post processing step. To improve the effectiveness of the approach, we also present an ensemble of decision trees which is shown to be more robust when the training data changes. Empirical tests are conducted on both a realistic insurance application domain and UCI benchmark data.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-211</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>TARFS (WITH READ/WRITE SUPPORT)</Project_Name>
	<Domain>SYSTEM APPLICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Tarfs is nothing but a file system in linux which aims at providing access to tar files without extracting the contents of tar archive. Currently tarfs is a READ ONLY file system.  Our aim is to provide WRITE support to tarfs. It will support adding files to the archive, deleting files from the archive and modifying existing files in the archive. This will save the time for untaring the tarball, modifying its contents and again re-taring it; especially when the size of tarball is very big. Also the disk space required to untar the tarball is saved. Other problems such as tarbomb (it is a tarball which explodes in current directory rather than creating a new directory) can be avoided using tar file system. This could prevent loss of important data or of files due to overwriting of files and directories that have same names and which reside in same directory.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-213</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>TWIN LINUX-RUNNING INDEPENDENT KERNELS SIMULTANEOUSLY ON SEPARATE CORES OF MULTI-CORE SYSTEMS FOR IMPROVING PERFORMANCE</Project_Name>
	<Domain>SYSTEM APPLICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>On current SMP architecture, there is only a single copy of the Linux kernel irrespective of the number of cores. Usual execution of Linux kernel is based on scheduling threads on all cores. This allows execution of multiple threads in parallel to achieve better performance. However, when the number of cores in a system goes on increasing, the overhead posed by scheduler is too high because of frequent switching and scheduling of threads across all cores. Running independent copies of kernels on different cores can be used for this scenario.  The idea is to run different copies of kernels simultaneously on different cores of a multi-core system and provide synchronization between the kernels using IPIs (Inter Processor Interrupts) and shared memory. This idea can be best used for servers where pipelined execution of tasks is possible. The available cores would be divided into groups according to the number of different tasks to be performed. By providing separate kernels (and in turn schedulers) for different tasks, the scheduler overhead will decrease significantly. This is the first project of its kind and it takes advantage of abundance of cores of a multi-core system by dedicating group of cores for every task increasing  code cache hit ratio. We present TwinLinux, an implementation of this scenario for 2 processing units using Intel Core 2 duo system. This idea works for – Filers, SCSI targets, and Graphics Processing Engines. This idea can be easily scaled, with minimal touch-up, for architectures with more than 2 cores.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-219</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>MIDDLEWARE FRAMEWORK FOR MULTI-TOUCH GESTURE SUPPORT IN LINUX BASED EMBEDED DEVICES</Project_Name>
	<Domain>SYSTEM APPLICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>The project aims to implement a middleware framework for Linux-based device implementations by providing support for multi-touch multi-pointer pluggable gestures like pinch in, pinch out, rotate, etc. Multi-touch is not yet introduced in mobiles based on true Linux UI architecture which use X window system and GTK+ toolkit. The middleware framework proposed uses multi-pointer X Window System (MPX) to identify simultaneous multiple inputs. MPX, mainly used in Linux Distributions, is used to accommodate multiple input devices, providing multiple mouse cursors and multiple keyboard foci. The central idea is to enhance this functionality of MPX to ensure the Multi-touch support and to eliminate the application-dependency, the Multi-touch gesture recognition, its heuristics and corresponding event handling modules need to be integrated in the middle-tier UI library.  The framework uses GTK+ toolkit, a GUI library that abstracts the MPX and the related protocol away from the user. GTK+ offers cross platform compatibility and an easy to use API. Further the capacitive touch-screens in mobile devices will respond to multi-device input, incase tslib driver is installed. On standalone machines, a synaptics touchpad driver will respond to such gestures. A great amount of work is being proposed to be done in GTK+ library and the touch drivers, both of which use the recently released MPX. In a nutshell, the idea attempts to establish a very novel, hardware and application independent open-source middleware framework, to incorporate the multi-touch gestures on any Linux-based device implementations.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-229</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>WINFLUX: FILE SYSTEMS IN WINDOWS USERSPACE- CHALLENGING THE STEREOTYPE</Project_Name>
	<Domain>SYSTEM APPLICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Currently file systems in Windows are integrated into the Kernel. Since implementing a traditional file system is extremely complex and difficult, presenting information seamlessly through files and folders has typically been limited to a small set of select programmers--often kernel hackers who develop at the lowest layers of a system. A simple alternative to this issue is to use the concept of file system in user space. This approach almost trivializes the process of making anything and everything appear seamlessly as a set of files and folders. Dokan Library is similar to FUSE but works on Windows. Dokan library traps the filesystem interrupts and passes them onto the Callback functions which are implemented by a user application. Using Dokan, we demonstrate the ease of this approach by taking the example of Extended file systems (Ext2/3). In this project the file system data structures (inodes, superblock, etc) along with their standard operations are implemented in the user space. This allows us to preserve the ideology of inodes in Linux File Systems too. Hence, this demonstrates that any type of data structure can be implemented in user space; irrespective of the ones defined in the kernel and therefore facilitates the development of Linux or any other file systems conveniently on Windows too.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-231</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>OPTIL\MAL VIRTUAL MACHINE PLACEMENT</Project_Name>
	<Domain>SYSTEM APPLICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Large network owners e.g. Software companies, Service providers, etc are facing a problem of large investments in infrastructure of computers. They are now moving towards virtualization as it provides a solution to this problem. Virtualization provides a way through by installing virtual machines (VM’s) as clients on large physical servers. But as the server becomes overloaded at times due to higher requirements of resources by the VM’s. It is needed to balance all the servers in the network and bring their utilization under a specific threshold, for better performance of the servers and VM’s. Considering the above requirements we propose a “Virtual Machine Resource Placement Algorithm”. This algorithm monitors the physical servers, and finds outs the overloaded server. It the checks for the proper VM which can be shifted from this server to another, and the chain continues till all the servers on which a new VM is shifted are brought under the threshold levels of their utilization levels. This improves the performance of the servers and hence of the clients. The algorithm at last gives the optimal number of virtual shifts required to be done and the virtual machines which are needed to be shifted and the servers on which they are to be shifted. This algorithm tries to reduce the time factor to give the shift results and also provides minimum number of shifts, which facilitates for real time implementation in large networks.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-233</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>ADDING KERNEL MODE SETTING SUPPORT TO CIRRUS CLGD5446 PCI VGA GRAPHICS CARD</Project_Name>
	<Domain>SYSTEM APPLICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>QEMU is a processor emulator that relies on dynamic binary translation to achieve a reasonable speed while being easy to port on new host Central processing Unit architecture .In configuration with Central Processing Unit emulation, it also provides a set of device model, allowing to run a variety of unmodified guest Operating Systems, it can thus be viewed as a hosted Virtual Machine monitor. Besides Central Processing Unit, QEMU emulates Cirrus CLGD5446 PCI VGA Card as its Graphics Card. Due to the lack of special device drivers for the Graphics Card, there is no hardware accelerated performance, and thus there is a large overhead for multimedia applications. The project intends to modify the existing drivers for Cirrus CLGD5446 PCI VGA Card to support important feature of Kernel Mode Settings (KMS). This would be achieved by an in-kernel direct rendering manager (DRM) driver. DRM is a component of the direct rendering infrastructure, a system to provide efficient video acceleration on UNIX like Operating System. It consists of two in-kernel drivers, a generic DRM driver and another which has specific support for the video hardware. Thus the pair of drivers allows a user space client direct access to video hardware. The final effect of re-writing driver would be seen on guest Operating System, as there would be seamless transition between two different screens. This project will enhance the graphical processing of the guest Operating System and will also result in faster boot up.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-235</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>CLOUD 9: A NOVEL APPROACH FOR RESOURCE AND PERFORMANCE OPTIMIZATION IN A CLOUD ENVIRONMENT</Project_Name>
	<Domain>SYSTEM APPLICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Load balancing and server consolidation algorithms used in data center environments cannot be effectively used in clouds. These algorithms are based on the assumption that the environment will be homogenous. However, in a cloud, we expect the environment to be heterogeneous. Cloud providers can hence significantly lower operational costs and improve hosted application performance by considering affinities and conflicts between virtual machines (VM’s). These affinities can be inferred from location-independent VM characterizations called virtual footprints. This is further used to reshape the physical footprint of a VM, which is its physical resource consumption, to achieve higher VM consolidation and application performance in a cloud environment. The placement and migration policies will intelligently place the VM’s on the appropriate physical servers based on parameters such as CPU usage, memory, network, as well as heuristics on the past statistics, in an optimal manner. The decisions will be based on network data dependencies, number of pages shared and CPU-intensive and I/O-intensive processes and other such principles. Finally, we also consider the after effects of a decision and try to mitigate a hotspot of this kind by relocating the VM causing the trigger. Some added features are that of initial placement and server consolidation algorithms, which run as and when required. Hence, we try to map a novel and comprehensive optimization solution in a cloud environment and also observe that the benefits to be achieved are tremendous.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-242</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>TAGGING APPROACH IN THE NAUTILUS FILE MANAGER</Project_Name>
	<Domain>SYSTEM APPLICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Nautilus is the official file manager for the GNOME desktop. It supports browsing of local file system. Beagle is a Linux desktop independent service which transparently keeps track of the data and provides searching and indexing capabilities. Certain applications can result in a set of files in which may be a part of different workspace. Using a traditional file system to store these files separately results in excessive use of disc and main memory file cache space. Instead of organizing documents in real folders, the documents are added to the system. Tagging is the ability to attach metadata with each file to make the file a part of different custom workspaces. When a file is to be made a part of multiple workspaces, tags are attached to the file .This approach helps to make a file a part of multiple workspaces without physical duplication and integrate searching in the file manager that will allow users to find and structure their files as they require, without needing to resort to awkward searches.We propose a solution to implement tagging approach in the Nautilus File Manager which aims to integrate search tool within the File Manager, thereby reducing the memory load individual applications incur</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-208</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>LOW-END EMBEDDED LINUX PLATFORM FOR NETWORK SECURITY APPLICATION- PORT SCANNING DETECTOR</Project_Name>
	<Domain>VLSI AND EMBEDDED TECHNOLOGIES</Domain>
	<Abstract>The purpose of this paper is to realize possible usage  on embedded Linux platform for Intrusion Detection (Port Scan Detection). The approach was to develop  the software which performs port scan using half-open  and udp technique. The software is then cross-compiled  for  ARM emulator. We hope to show that the  Embedded Port Scan Detector (EPSD) unit managed to be at par with the other known port scanning software, besides running on relatively low-end  embedded platform. Hence, it is significant that the  product has a very high market potential.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-302</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>VLSI BASED REMOTE PROCESS CONTROL</Project_Name>
	<Domain>VLSI AND EMBEDDED TECHNOLOGIES</Domain>
	<Abstract>Many industries deal with extreme conditions like high process temperatures, environments involving hazardous chemicals, and even some monotonous procedures. These processes have a fixed set of operations to be performed under normal conditions. However some conditions do arise when the process parameters cross standard levels. This can lead to some unprecedented results. One solution to this problem is to employ a person to monitor the process parameters and take decisions accordingly. However it is not possible for a human being to withstand extreme conditions. Other solution is to install intelligent devices that might do this job. We propose to design a system that will monitor the process parameters and inform the field engineer whenever the conditions exceed the normal levels. VLSI based REMOTE PROCESS CONTROL is a device that will sense extreme conditions and inform the field engineer through a short messaging service (SMS). The field engineer will analyse the situation and decide the action to be performed. He will send back the necessary instructions to the control circuit through a SMS. The control circuit on receipt of the instruction will act accordingly.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-303</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>HARDWARE REALIZATION OF OPTIMIZED DIRECT FORM FIR FILTER ON FPGA</Project_Name>
	<Domain>VLSI AND EMBEDDED TECHNOLOGIES</Domain>
	<Abstract>DSP Algorithms are described by non-terminating programs which execute the same code repetitively. The basic operation in any DSP Algorithm is SOP (Sum of Products). It is usually implemented by using a series of delays, multipliers, and adders to create the filters output. Execution of all the computations in the algorithm once is referred to as iteration. The iteration period is the time required for execution of one iteration of the algorithm. Finite impulse response (FIR) filters are the most popular type of filters implemented in software and can be used to implement almost any sort of frequency response digitally and hence used in implementation of most of the DSP Applications. Existing methods of filter implementation require more arithmetic operations, hardware components and Execution/Iteration time. The main targets of VLSI optimization are Area, Time and Power. We aim at optimizing the filter design in terms of Time and Power requirement. We intend to use techniques like *Pipelining to increase the clock speed and *Parallel Processing to produce multiple outputs in a clock cycle, thereby inproving the time performance of the filter. FPGA will be used to implement the FIR Filter. VHDL code for the filter will be downloaded on FPGA. Field Programmable Gate Array is a type of logic chip that can be programmed and is especially popular for prototyping integrated circuit designs. Once the design is set, hardwired chips are produced for faster performance.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-305</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>FPGA BASED IMAGE COMPRESSION USING JPEG STANDARD</Project_Name>
	<Domain>VLSI AND EMBEDDED TECHNOLOGIES</Domain>
	<Abstract>To achieve a balance between high performance and energy efficiency embedded systems often use heterogeneous multiprocessor platforms tuned for a well defined application domain. However, due to extremely high design cost and NRE for deep submicron IC, not many applications can afford that type of ICs. An alternative solution is FPGA-based multiprocessor system. In this way, both high programmability and low risk can be obtained. Recent research shows such a system which loses only 2.6X in performance (normalized) compared to a dedicated ASIP for IP packet forwarding application . In this project, we demonstrate the design flow of an FPGA-based multiprocessor system for high performance multimedia application and explore different on-chip interconnects for multiprocessor system. We construct a JPEG encoder on multiprocessor on Xilinx Virtex-II Pro FPGA. The design can compress a BMP image into a JPG image in high speed. We also implement different interconnects between processors, including bus, dualport memory, FIFO  and explore the trade-off between them.The advantage of FPGA approach is (1) low design cost and turnaround time which means low investment and risk. (2) Designers can customize the multiprocessor system for a target application, especially by interconnection and hardware accelerators. (3) Retains  multiprocessor programming model and provides an easy way to map application from existing code base. (4) Support for system iteration design method. Designers can iteratively optimize the system on the real, existing system instead of simulation and estimation. JPEG compression is defined as a lossy coding system which is based on the discrete cosine transform. However, there are several extensions to the JPEG algorithm to  provide greater compression, higher precision, and can be tailored to specific applications.  It can also be used as a lossless coding system that may be necessary for applications requiring precise image restoration.  JPEG has four defined extension modes: sequential DCT based, progressive DCT based, lossless, and hierarchical mode."/></Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-313</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>AUTOMATIC HEAD LAMP CONTROL SYSTEM</Project_Name>
	<Domain>VLSI AND EMBEDDED TECHNOLOGIES</Domain>
	<Abstract>An automatic head lamp control system can be used inexpensively and for a long term by reducing the unpleasant feeling of the driver. Here according to the steering movement the lamp on the wheel is automatically turns the direction which is handled by microcontroller. It is easy to drive the vehicle at any junctions or bend roads. This project relates to an automatic head-lamp control system for vehicle that tilts and adjusts automatically an optical axis of a headlamp based on an inclination of a vehicle in the longitudinal direction and, more particularly, an auto-controlling system for vehicle headlamp that is effective for the vehicle driver. This is automatically done through finding the direction of inclination of steering and according to that it can adjust the lamp position. The potentiometer is connected in-between steering and microcontroller. According to the steering movement the potentiometer generates the voltage and it is given to microcontroller through A/D converter. Depends on that, the Microcontroller activates the relay to adjust the angle of the lamp. It is all done automatically which ease the work of driver.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-320</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>DATA LOGGING SYSTEM FOR A BATCHING PLANT</Project_Name>
	<Domain>VLSI AND EMBEDDED TECHNOLOGIES</Domain>
	<Abstract>In many automation industries, there are many processes or activities running simultaneously. If there are any breakdowns in these processes, there is a need to analyze the data for diagnosis. As without which the root cause for the breakdown won’t be visible. So there is a need for efficient data logging in such systems. Logging the processor data in the USB drive is the best-suited option for analysis in these days. Because these devices have no moving parts, theyre more durable than other forms of removable media in environments that produce a lot of dust or humidity. This makes USB drives more useful in application area where the controllers are remotely accessible for analyzing. Pen drives have an added advantage of compatibility with PC running on any OS and also the data can be viewed in any desired format.So we have developed an add-on module, which will log the data of a dedicated system like the batching plant in cement industry and make it available for analysis on a thumb drive. We have also developed a reliable serial communication protocol between our module and the process controller. The data will consist of the quantity of ingredients in cement mixing for each batch in order and it will also indicate the total weight. Our system will replace the printers and EEPROM’s in existing embedded system and provide efficient data logging and fault analysis.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-323</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>TRAINING AND DECODING OF AMERICAN SIGN LANGUAGE</Project_Name>
	<Domain>VLSI AND EMBEDDED TECHNOLOGIES</Domain>
	<Abstract>We have to create a glove that learns different signs and saves these signs into microcontroller. Our implementation of the glove only deals with the 26 letters of the English alphabet that can be directly translated into American Sign Language (ASL). The part of our project that is different from other gloves is that after programming these letters into the microcontroller, letters are chosen at random for the student to practice and learn. The LCD display is used as a reference for how much more or less you need to bend each finger to correctly sign a letter. The student must then adjust their hand position to match the prompted letter within some specified range in order to be able to move on to the next letter. The apparatus is provided with a keypad to program in the different hand positions of the alphabet. There are two switches signifying TRAIN mode and LEARN mode. Depending upon the switch pressed,the mode of operation will be selected. In order to input the position, a respective number of the alphabet must be pressed on the keypad. Following that, the position of the letter must be held for approximately 3 seconds. The user is expected not to know ASL and can use a table of sign language letters for reference or call in an American Sign Language expert to help the student perfect the letters of the alphabet.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-326</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>RECONFIGURABLE FPGA</Project_Name>
	<Domain>VLSI AND EMBEDDED TECHNOLOGIES</Domain>
	<Abstract>The computation and configuration sequences as well as the data exchange are defined at compile time and never change during a computation. This approach is more interesting for devices, which can only be fully reconfigured. However, it can be applied to partial reconfigurable devices that are logically or physically partitioned in a set of reconfigurablebins.In configuration assignment, the task is partitioned into subtasks, and each subtask is assigned to a configuration according to an execution order. Then in storage resource assignment, the intermediate data between configurations are assigned to storage resource.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-327</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>SMART ENERGY METER</Project_Name>
	<Domain>VLSI AND EMBEDDED TECHNOLOGIES</Domain>
	<Abstract>The energy metering technology used presently in India is not highly reliable and requires substantial labour and time to read meter reading. The present electricity meters are not only less accurate but also due to its complex analog circuitry used having high power consumption. So we are developing a system which will not only eradicate all the disadvantages (including tampering) of the present day meters but also make use of the wireless technology.Thus our “Smart Meter” is an advancement in electricity meter which will make our present billing system free from wastage of man power making it convenient to the society. For this purpose we are making use of microcontroller MSP430FE427 which is having very low power consumption. The meter readings will be transmitted from the ZigBee module. We are using a remote control to receive these readings. We use ZigBee which is an easy installation platform, cost effective method for the low bit rate transmission, so with the help of the ready ZigBee platform by using the assembly/c language we interface the module with the meter. In the remote control, we store all these readings using controller and LCD will display these readings. With the wireless transmission we not only have an accurate data but when compared to the analog failures the errors are very minimum. Thus the whole idea is to digitize the present system and take a step towards energy conservation.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-328</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>BRAILLE CALCULATOR</Project_Name>
	<Domain>VLSI AND EMBEDDED TECHNOLOGIES</Domain>
	<Abstract>To develop Braille display, we will be carrying out embossing of Braille digits on the rubber-band.This rubber band will be mounted on the wheel which we will rotate with the help of stepper motor. Accordingly there will be four wheels to display four digit answer.The same four digit answer will be announced on speaker digit by digit using audio processingIC APR6016 which requires 3.3V for its operation which is obtained using LD1117 .P89V51 operates at 5V and APR 6016 at 3.3V. Therefore to communicate  between the two we are using IC AT89C2051,whose operating volage ranges from 2.7V-6V.The result will be conveyed to microcontroller AT 89C2051  through serial communication. This microcontroller will send commands to APR6016 to announce the result.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-330</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>FPGA IMPLEMENTATION OF HANDWRITTEN DEVNAGARI NUMERICALS</Project_Name>
	<Domain>VLSI AND EMBEDDED TECHNOLOGIES</Domain>
	<Abstract>In OCR, a number to be recognized can be printed or handwritten characters/numerals. There are several approaches that deal with problem of recognition of numerals depending on the type of feature extracted and different way of extracting them. Our work is focused on a technique in feature extraction and classification. The features are fed to FPGA via serial communication (using uart) and model developed inside FPGA will recognize digit entered we are using specific  bmp image of devanagri digit as an input for our application. The image is scanned using HP flat bed scanner. The obtained image is converted into suitable format. As we have done some basic programming in MATLAB, we prefer MATLAB based image processing. The work proceeds as: Binarization, Get the margins, Cutting and resizing image, Cropping image fields, Filtering image, Feature extraction. FPGA will be used to implement of the reorganization algorithm. VHDL code for the Simulation and Classification, Display Results will be downloaded on FPGA. Field Programmable Gate Array is a type of logic chip that can be programmed and is especially popular for prototyping integrated circuit designs. Once the design is set, hardwired chips are produced for faster performance. We have also worked with Adaline algorithm and will finally proceed with the optimized. This subject has attracted immense research interest not only because of very challenging nature of the problem, but also because it provides the means for automatic processing of large volumes of data ithms are described by non-terminating programs which execute the same code repetitively. Traditionally, Devanagri digit Recognition algorithms are developed and implemented in the software media. With growing applications of FPGA chips, implementing a Devanagri digit Recognition algorithm on this hardware is desired. Portability, affordability and speed of optical character recognition implemented on the hardware are among the main goals for hardware implementation of an OCR algorithm on FP</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-331</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>CAN SNIFFER</Project_Name>
	<Domain>VLSI AND EMBEDDED TECHNOLOGIES</Domain>
	<Abstract>Controller Area Network(CAN) developed by Bosch is a popular protocol used for In Vehicle Communication System(IVCS).It is a differential serial communication standard used for establishing communication between various Electronic Control Units(ECU) in modern automotives, automation industries and defense systems. Sometimes the ECUs could be faulty or there could be some problem with the network cables. It is extremely difficult to manually find on field which ECU is faulty. The ECUs are costly and hence cannot be replaced easily. A good way to find out the exact problem in the network is to debug the CAN signals using a PC and a software program loaded in it. CAN protocol signals are not compatible with PC. We need to convert the CAN signals into signals recognized by the PC. We intend to implement a system which converts CAN signals into USB/RS232 level. A driver program recognizes the data entering through a particular port. A software program with a GUI will read this data as its inputs and execute accordingly with the help of which user would be able to take decisions. The designers of a typical automotive electronics system always face problems while developing CAN network with multiple ECUs communicating on standard or customized CAN protocol. The said tool is going to help designers as it will leverage the power of PC interface in understanding the communication happening in CAN layer. Thus when fully developed the said tool would be a ‘plug and play module’ used as a powerful debugger by Field Application Engineers for troubleshooting vehicular CAN networks.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-340</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>16*2 DOT MATRIX LED DISPLAY</Project_Name>
	<Domain>VLSI AND EMBEDDED TECHNOLOGIES</Domain>
	<Abstract>Nowadays 16*2 LCD’s are being used widely in shop floors, printers, petrol pumps, etc. But following are the drawbacks of this display device viz. 1] Distance limitation 2] Viewing angle limitation 3] Contrast and back light effect To overcome above mentioned disadvantages we are using 5*7 dot matrix LED displays. The prominent advantage of our display is that the code written for LCD need not be changed. Along with this the distance from which we can read the information is also increased to great extent. The viewing angle is increased to 180 because of LEDs. Taking the device compatibility into consideration, the modified display device will also have 16 pins as that of present LCD.   The basic technology used is Master-Slave. We are using 32 5*7 dot matrix cells to form 16*2 displays.A single 8051 microcontroller will control four such basic cells and thus we used 8 slaves to control all the basic cells. These eight slaves will be controlled by a single 8051 microcontroller acting as a master.The communication between master and slaves is bidirectional and it is a pure serial communication. The master will accept the data from user microcontroller and will give to respective slaves after interpreting it. Each slave microcontroller will have a unique device ID and the data will be displayed on corresponding display device.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-341</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>IMPLEMENTATION AND PERFORMANCE ANALYSIS OF DIGITAL MULTIPLIERS</Project_Name>
	<Domain>VLSI AND EMBEDDED TECHNOLOGIES</Domain>
	<Abstract>Speed and smaller area are some of the important criteria for the fabrication of DSP systems and high performance systems. Optimizing the speed and area of the multiplier is a major design issue. However, area and speed are usually conflicting constraints so that improving speed results mostly in larger area. In our project we try to determine the best solution to this problem by comparing some multipliers. High speed multiplication can be achieved either by reducing the number of partial products or by adding the partial products faster.  This project presents an efficient implementation of high speed multiplier using fast adders like carry save adder, Wallace tree adder and methods like Booth, Modified Booth, and Modified Booth-Wallace tree. However, the disadvantage of time consumption of these techniques has not been completely removed. Vedic mathematics is the name given to the technique of calculations based on simple rules. It is based on 16 sutras. It was rediscovered from ancient Indian scriptures by Sri Bharati Krishna Tirthaji, a scholar of Sanskrit, mathematics, history and philosophy. Hence, the exploration of Vedic algorithms in DSP domain may prove to be extremely advantageous. So our project also aims at designing a multiplier based on Vedic mathematics using the Urdhava Tiryakbhyam technique. The parallel multipliers like Vedic, Modified Booth multiplier do computation using lesser adders and lesser steps. As a result their speed is high and they occupy lesser space. In this project we first designed different type of multipliers using techniques like Vedic method, Booth, Modified Booth and adders like carry save adder, Wallace tree adder. Then we compared the different multipliers on the basis of speed to determine the fastest multiplier. The result of our project helps us to choose a better multiplier in fabricating different systems. Multipliers are an important component of many systems. So analyzing the working of different multipliers helps to frame a better system.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-311</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>PLC BASED AUTOMATION SYSTEM</Project_Name>
	<Domain>INSTRUMENTATION AND CONTROL</Domain>
	<Abstract>With the price reductions and technical advances, applications for PLCs have mushroomed. PLCs are increasingly used to connect and work with other computer, automated systems and components. Use of PLCs has also expanded in safety systems and redundancy for greater reliability. The growing need for PLC training parallels the expanding market for the devices. Definition of PLC by NEMA(National Electrical Manufacturers Association):A PLC is a digitally operated electronic system, designed for industrial environment, which uses a programmable memory for the internal storage of user instructions (program) for implementing specific functions such as logic, sequencing,timing, counting and arithmetic to control through (digital or analog inputs and outputs), the various types of machines or processes.
The main difference from other computers is that PLCs are armored for severe conditions (such as dust, moisture, heat, cold) and have the facility for extensive  (I/O) arrangements. These connect the PLC to sensors and actuators PLCs read limit switches, analog process variables (such as temperature and pressure), and the positions of complex positioning systems. Some use machine vision. On the actuator side, PLCs operate on electric  motors ,pneumatic or hydrolics cylinders, magnetic solenoids and relays or analog outputs. The input/output arrangements may be built into a simple PLC, or the PLC may have external I/O modules attached to a computer network that plugs into the PLC.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-314</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>ELECTRONIC ENERGY METER POWER FACTOR CORRECTOR</Project_Name>
	<Domain>INSTRUMENTATION AND CONTROL</Domain>
	<Abstract>Energy conservation is lively and expanding field, whose main goal is to reduce energy consumption from various instruments. Our aim is to build an Electronic Energy Meter which will measure energy consumption and power factor of load (most likely motor). Here, with energy meter we are also going to design a power factor corrector unit. According to calculated power factor, Power factor corrector unit will take proper decision to improve power factor of load. Due to improved power factor, loss of energy in the instrument gets reduced. BASIC WORKING: 1.We will give input from line and neutral to voltage and current transformers. 2.ADC will convert analog voltage into digital voltage n feed it to microprocessor. 3.Digital phase meter unit will calculate power difference between V and I and send it to microprocessor. 4.Microprocessor will calculate energy and power factor. 5.According to programming of the microprocessor, it will select the capacitors from the capacitor bank using relays to improve the power factor.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-318</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>WIRELESS GAS DETECTION SYSTEM</Project_Name>
	<Domain>INSTRUMENTATION AND CONTROL</Domain>
	<Abstract>The project is aimed to develop a system to detect leakage of L.P.G gas. The system includes a gas sensor which helps to detect the odorless component of the gas. The gas sensor (TiO2 –Poly aniline) does not need pre heating for its working. The gas sensor works at normal room temperature, unlike other heated type gas sensors. Also the sensor shows exceptional sensitivity towards L.P.G. The sensor is interfaced with signal conditioning circuitry. The sensor is powered at constant voltage by a 0-5V power supply. A set of RF transceivers is used for wireless communication. The transmitter set will transmit the data from the sensor to the other end. The receiver will be connected to the computer which will help maintain the log about the leakage level. The pc interface will enable us to access the data from any remote location. With the use of wireless communication, the module can be used in situations where there is danger to human life apart from its normal usage. A centralized network can be used to monitor several sensors at a time.As soon as the detector senses the gas levels are above the prescribed levels, it automatically sends and sms to the mobile.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-333</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>NAVIGATION OF GUN SYSTEM</Project_Name>
	<Domain>INSTRUMENTATION AND CONTROL</Domain>
	<Abstract>The battlefield scenario is undergoing constant changes and various advancements have been done in the weapon systems to suit diverse environments and tactics .Technology related to defense has been modified  tremendously after second world war.  This has brought about a need for faster engagement of targets with higher precision. In order to negate the time lag between acquiring and engagement of targets various systems are under development.That being the backdrop the idea of ‘DESIGN AND DEVELOPMENT OF   AUTOMATIC GUN CONTROL SYSTEM’ was conceptualized. The system is designed to acquire the target given by the operator and accordingly adjust the position of the gun and fire the gun at located position. Thus such systems will save the time and most important precious life of soldiers. It will reduce the time lag between acquisition and engagement of the target.Unmanned ground vehicles and Unmanned aerial vehicles like drone made by USA are working on the same technology and can cover very large area and thereby increasing our range of operation.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-226</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>V2SCAN (VOIP VULNERABILITY SCANNER)</Project_Name>
	<Domain>MULTIMEDIA</Domain>
	<Abstract>Businesses are gradually beginning to migrate from traditional copper-wire telephone systems to VoIP systems due to advantages including bandwidth efficiency and low costs that Voice Over IP technology can provide. As the technology has grown in popularity, VoIP has also got a serious security crunch which includes spoofing, hijacking, buffer overflow, spamming, and phishing attacks. Due to such loopholes in the VoIP infrastructure, the challenge is to develop some descent security testers and anti-hackers.Considering the above requirements we propose a “VoIP Vulnerability Scanner(V2SCAN)”. This tool will act as a third party assessment tool, which assess the robustness of VoIP infrastructure against various security threats and vulnerabilities. This framework will scan the infrastructure in order to check how secure the implementation is by performing some of the well-known attacks. There are various ways in which vulnerabilities in VoIP can be exploited. The basic need of Framework is to test using some of such methods in deployment environment and unearth the flaws, if exists, to network administrator or customer who uses VoIP products. Once vulnerabilities are identified, it provides remedial information that enables security professionals to perform appropriate actions. Thus user can rely on this tool to verify vendor claims and penetrate the VoIP deployment for finding vulnerabilities in the network.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-132</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>VIDEO STEGANOGRAPHY USING LSB EMBEDDING TECHNIQUE BY RANDOM SELECTION OF PIXELS</Project_Name>
	<Domain>DITAL SIGNAL PROCESSING / IMAGE PROCESSING / SPEECH PROCESSING</Domain>
	<Abstract>The word Steganography derived from two Greek word steganos, meaning “covered,”  and graphia meaning “to write”. Is the art and science of hiding the fact that communication is taking  place. LSB embedding is widely used for its high hiding capacity, here we are using this approach to defeat with one of powerful steganalysis method i.e SPA ( Sample Pair Analysis ) by using random embedding method of  LSB embedding on video. Using video steganography we can embed a secret document inside a piece of unsuspicious information such as video  and send it without anyone knowing of the existence of the secret document Here we are providing three way security by 1.Providing keys for data exchange 2. Encrypting the private information to be send. 3. Embedding  encrypted information  in video file.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-134</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>REAL TIME HAND GESTURE RECOGNITION</Project_Name>
	<Domain>DITAL SIGNAL PROCESSING / IMAGE PROCESSING / SPEECH PROCESSING</Domain>
	<Abstract>Today, the world is changing on a day to day basis. On the way to create the world free of computer and mouse, touch screen were introduced. We have gone one step further and have created a software by which the human computer interaction using hand gestures. This is one of the latest topics in the research field of human computer interaction (HCI) and uses webcam to interpret hand gestures and performs the operations of mouse and keyboard. We have shown this through by performing applications like image browsing, scaling and rotation and gaming. The “Gesture Pro-a Real Time Hand Gesture Recognition System” is a novel idea and has its aim to make keyboard, mouse, joystick and other such input devices obsolete. This project is a small step on its way to achieve the above idea.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-135</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>SIGN TO VOICE SYSTEM (S2V)</Project_Name>
	<Domain>DITAL SIGNAL PROCESSING / IMAGE PROCESSING / SPEECH PROCESSING</Domain>
	<Abstract>Hand gesture is one of the typical methods used in sign language for non-verbal communication. It is mostly used by hearing and speech impaired people as an effective communicative medium amongst themselves and others. Various sign language systems have been developed by manufacturers around the globe but they are neither flexible nor cost-effective for the end users. This project proposes a system prototype that is able to automatically recognize sign language to help people communicate more effectively with the hearing or speech impaired people. Different sets of universal hand gestures are captured from web camera and utilized to train the neural network for classification purpose.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-241</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>FILTERING IMAGE SPAM WITH NEAR DUPLICATE DETECTION</Project_Name>
	<Domain>DITAL SIGNAL PROCESSING / IMAGE PROCESSING / SPEECH PROCESSING</Domain>
	<Abstract>Image spam is junk e-mail that includes an image instead of just text. Image spam poses a great threat to email communications due to high volumes, bigger bandwidth requirements, and higher processing requirements for filtering. To combat computer vision techniques such as OCR, spammers have begun applying CAPTCHA (Completely Automated Public Turing Test to Tell Computers and Humans Apart) techniques. These techniques distort the original image or add colorful or noisy backgrounds so that only humans can identify the intended message. Once spammers have applied an image creation algorithm to make a message difficult to detect with computer vision algorithms, they apply further randomization to construct a batch of images for delivery. The additional randomization defeats hash-based detection mechanisms. Hence a image spam filter with near duplicate detection by using color histogram, haar wavelet and orientation histogram for capturing randomization effects made in spam image. The project provides us a system in which we can have comprehensive control over the infiltration of image based spam. This project hopes to reduce effectively costs faced by large organizations, such as multinational enterprises, universities, and governments.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-301</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>COMPLETE SECURITY SYSTEM FOR AUTOMOBILES</Project_Name>
	<Domain>DITAL SIGNAL PROCESSING / IMAGE PROCESSING / SPEECH PROCESSING</Domain>
	<Abstract>Our project provides complete security for automobiles in three respects : 1.Driver Verification to Prevent Theft/Intrusion:To verify identity, we shall install a webcam at the entry of the vehicle. A match is then searched within the database, using Discrete Cosine Transform to extract useful details from the subject’s face. This ensures that a user is allowed to enter the vehicle only if previously authorized to drive the automobile. Such testing is not done for the passenger seats. In case of doubt regarding the driver’s identity, the ignition is prohibited.This avoids vehicle theft using duplicate keys or forced intrusion into the driver’s seat. 2.Drunken Driving Prevention:For alcohol detection, we shall use the MQ-3 Alcohol sensor from Hanwei Electronics. This sensor detects ethanol in the air and due to a certain chemical reaction occurring inside the sensor, a voltage is generated.By setting a certain voltage threshold according to tests conducted, the output can be classified as Drunk\Not Drunk. Due to the nature of the sensor, calibration cannot be performed. Therefore, the level of drunkenness cannot be displayed. This is one disadvantage, although it still allows us to prevent drunken driving. 3.Drowsiness Detection:For drowsiness detection, a continuous video feed of the driver is taken. If closure of eyelids is detected, a timer is started. If the eyes are found to be closed even after a predetermined amount of time, an alarm signal is given, which awakens the driver and prevents accidents due to excessive drowsiness.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-306</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>VOLUMETRIC ANALYSIS OF LEFT VENTRICLE</Project_Name>
	<Domain>DITAL SIGNAL PROCESSING / IMAGE PROCESSING / SPEECH PROCESSING</Domain>
	<Abstract>Cardiac Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) is a non invasive medical test that helps physicians diagnose and treat medical conditions. A single cardiac examination results in a large amount of image data. Manual analysis by experts is time consuming and also susceptible to intra- and inter-observer variability. This leads to the urgent requirement for efficient image segmentation algorithms to automatically extract clinically relevant parameters.           The volume of blood flowing into the left ventricle in one cardiac cycle provides useful quantitative and qualitative information for diagnosis of certain heart conditions. Therefore, our project basically deals with the analysis of the left ventricle of the human heart by processing the Magnetic Resonance Images. We propose to have accurate left ventricle (LV) segmentations across a cardiac cycle. The existing LV segmentation techniques are founded mostly upon algorithms for segmenting static images. Whereas, our project will facilitate the segmentation and analysis of dynamic images by saving them as frames. The segmentation at each particular time is based not only on the data observed at that instant, but also on predictions based on past segmentations. Our framework uses a curve evolution method to combine such predictions with the observed images to estimate the LV boundaries at each time. Further, the volumetric analysis of the segmented image will give us the quantity of blood that enters the left ventricle in one cardiac cycle. This is the final output of our project.

</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-310</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>TEXTURE ANALYSIS AND CLASSIFICATION</Project_Name>
	<Domain>DITAL SIGNAL PROCESSING / IMAGE PROCESSING / SPEECH PROCESSING</Domain>
	<Abstract>Texture refers to the properties that represent the surface or structure of an object. It is something consisting of mutually related elements.Texture analysis is an important and useful area of study in machine vision. Most natural surfaces exhibit texture and a successful vision system must be able to deal with the textured world surrounding it. However, images of real objects often do not exhibit regions of uniform intensities. The patterns can be the result of physical surface properties such as roughness or oriented strands which often have a tactile quality, or they could be the result of reflectance differences such as the color on a surface. Today, texture analysis plays an important role in many tasks, ranging from remote sensing to medical imaging and query by content in large image databases.The main aim of texture analysis is texture recognition and texture based shape analysis. We can define texture as coarse, fine, grained, smooth etc. These features can be found in the tone and structure of a texture. A texture primitive is a contagious set of pixels with some tonal and regional property, and can be described by its properties. The relationship can be random, or pairwise dependent, or mutually dependent. Image texture is then described by the number and types of primitives and by their spatial relationship. Texture analysis has four problem domains namely Texture Classification, Texture Segmentation, Texture Synthesis and Shape from Texture.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-312</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>IMPLEMENTATION OF ACOUSTIC SYSTEM</Project_Name>
	<Domain>DITAL SIGNAL PROCESSING / IMAGE PROCESSING / SPEECH PROCESSING</Domain>
	<Abstract>The rapid growth of technology in recent decades has changed the whole dimension of communications. Today people are more interested in hands-free communication. In such a situation, the use a regular loudspeaker and a high-gain microphone, in place of a telephone receiver, might seem more appropriate. This would allow more than one person to participate in a conversation at the same time such as a teleconference environment. Another advantage is that it would allow the person to have both hands free and to move freely in the room. However, the presence of a large acoustic coupling between the loudspeaker and microphone would produce a loud echo that would make conversation difficult. Furthermore, the acoustic system could become instable, which would produce a loud howling noise to occur. The solution to these problems is the elimination of the echo with an echo  suppression or echo cancellation algorithm. The echo suppressor offers a simple but effective method to counter the echo problem. However, the echo suppressor possesses a main disadvantage since it supports only half-duplex communication. Half-duplex communication permits only one speaker to talk at a time. This drawback led to the invention of echo cancellers. An important aspect of echo cancellers is that full-duplex communication can be maintained, which allows both speakers to talk at the same time. This objective of this research was to produce an improved echo cancellation algorithm, which is capable of providing convincing results. The three basic components of an echo canceller are an adaptive filter, a doubletalk detector and a nonlinear processor. The adaptive filter creates a replica of the echo and subtracts it from the combination of the actual echo and the near-end signal. The doubletalk detector senses the doubletalk. Doubletalk occurs when both ends are talking, which stops the adaptive filter in order to avoid divergence. Finally, the nonlinear processor removes the residual echo from the error signal. Usually, a certain amount of speech is clipped in the final stage of nonlinear processing. In order to avoid clipping, a noise gate was used as a nonlinear processor in this research. The noise gate allowed a threshold value to be set and all signals below the threshold were removed. This action ensured that only residual echoes were removed in the final stage. To date, the real time implementation of echo an cancellation algorithm was performed by utilizing both a VLSI processor and a DSP processor. Since there has been a revolution in the field of personal computers, in recent years, this research attempted to implement the acoustic echo canceller algorithm on a natively running PC with the help of the MATLAB software.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-316</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>SMART GESTURES</Project_Name>
	<Domain>DITAL SIGNAL PROCESSING / IMAGE PROCESSING / SPEECH PROCESSING</Domain>
	<Abstract>Our problem statement is to incorporate gestures in the human-computer interaction in order to make it intuitive and user-friendly. We present a framework that equips computers with dynamic gesture recognition capabilities. In our system, motion encodes dynamic information, and we extract features from the gestural space that are otherwise unavailable to conventional input devices. We define a gesture as a movement of a part of the body, to express an idea or meaning. Thus, waving goodbye is a gesture, while pressing a key on a keyboard is not. In the latter, all that matters is which key was pressed; the motion of a finger on the way to hitting a key is neither observed nor significant. The most widely used quasi-gesture equipped device is the "single point" mouse, which is limited in the degrees of freedom it facilitates. Touchscreens have come a long way in improving communication between humans and devices. However, they are accompanied by the drawback that a fixed frame of reference is established for every gesture. Gestures come intuitively to humans. For example, a beckoning gesture is enough to convey all the information to be communicated. In addition, the way the gesture is executed conveys whether the gesture is a loving one or an aggressive one. Our objective is first to equip computers with 2D vision to recognize gestures that can simplify mainstream tasks that are ordinarily performed using a mouse or a joystick, and further to enable stereoscopic computer vision that can detect taps or clicks.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-319</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>IMAGE CATCHER</Project_Name>
	<Domain>DITAL SIGNAL PROCESSING / IMAGE PROCESSING / SPEECH PROCESSING</Domain>
	<Abstract>Mobile robotics is a lively and expanding research field, whose main goal is the development of autonomous robots that can freely interact in dynamic environments. Some of the main problems to be solved are the ones of perception, navigation, dynamic map building, self-localization, and mapping and tracking of mobile objects. In this project we focus on the resolution of last two problems, self localization and mapping and tracking of moving objects.Our aim is to build an autonomous robot which will follow the ball based on the principles of  1.Colour recognition 2.Shape recognition. Among all the visual features, color is perhaps the most distinguishing one in many applications. Next commonly used features for image recognition is it’s shape.In this project  we are exploiting these two features for differentiating the ball of user’s concern from other background objects. BASIC WORKING: 1.The camera on the robot will capture the image and send it to PC (via wireless USB interface). 2.The PC installed with MATLAB will process the image and differentiate the concerned object (ball) from its background. 3.It will further take decision based on the position\movement of object and give the same signal to the microcontroller on robot side through wireless module and microcontroller unit on PC side. 4.This microcontroller will then give control signals to the motors to guide the robot to the appropriate direction.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-322</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>DIGITAL RECOGNITION OF HAIRLINE FRACTURE</Project_Name>
	<Domain>DITAL SIGNAL PROCESSING / IMAGE PROCESSING / SPEECH PROCESSING</Domain>
	<Abstract>Fractures of bone are a common affliction. In most developed countries the number of fractures associated with age-related bone loss is increasing rapidly. Each year many fractures are missed during x-ray diagnosis, resulting in ineffective patient management and expensive litigation. From both an orthopaedic and radiologic point of view, the fully automatic detection and classification of fractures in long-bones is an important but difficult problem. In this paper, a fully automated method of detecting fractures in the diaphysis of a long-bone is described. X-rays are very difficult to process automatically, so to extract the required information various image processing techniques were implemented to smooth the image without losing information about the location of boundaries within the image. Next, artificial neural networks are used to detect the fracture and  an iterative peak detection algorithm is used to accurately locate the bone centerline and  articular  surfaces. A method based on orthogonal projections calculated from a modified Hough transform is used to automatically locate the long-bone diaphysis. At this point, our algorithm accurately localizes the area of the fracture, and would allow further image registration if necessary. Finally, a gradient-based algorithm is used to detect fractures present in the region of interest. The magnitude and direction of the gradient are combined to produce a measure of the likelyhood of the presence of a fracture. A library of long-bone fracture images was created. Experimental tests performed on a series of x-ray images show that the method is capable of accurately segmenting the diaphysis from the epiphyses, and is also able to detect many mid-shaft fractures of long-bones.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-325</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>REGION OF INTEREST TRACKING IN VIDEO</Project_Name>
	<Domain>DITAL SIGNAL PROCESSING / IMAGE PROCESSING / SPEECH PROCESSING</Domain>
	<Abstract>The basic aim of this project is to track the moving object in video (.AVI) within a defined region of interest in a video using background subtraction algorithm. This algorithm is implemented in following steps.Frame to frame tracking: Video is basically a number of frames. For a moving object its coordinates will change from frame to frame. So we will be comparing each frame to previous frame to find the objects in the region of interest. In this way a moving object would be identified in the given video.Segmentation: Segmentation is basically to partition the image. An image may contain various parts, by segmentation we would be able to identify various parts of the image and then they would form various segments.. The number of pixels having similar pixel value would form a segment. Background Subtraction: After segmentation the given frame would be dividing into a number of segments. The basic aim here would to separate the interested object from the rest of the object. All the segments in the given frame, except object of the interest would be clubbed together. After that the all the segments which do not contain the object of interest would not be considered.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-329</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>IMPLEMENTATION OF MP3 ENCODER ON DSP</Project_Name>
	<Domain>DITAL SIGNAL PROCESSING / IMAGE PROCESSING / SPEECH PROCESSING</Domain>
	<Abstract>The aim of our project was to write our own MPEG-1 Layer-3 encoder on DSP TMS320C6713 which has compression ratio of 12:1.   The MP3 compression algorithm could be executed faster and more efficiently on the DSP.  By developing code in Code Composer Studio based on this ISO standard algorithm, these stages could be executed on the DSP TMS320C6713.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-332</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>AUTOMATIC SEGMENTATION AND RECOGNATION OF BANK CHEQUE</Project_Name>
	<Domain>DITAL SIGNAL PROCESSING / IMAGE PROCESSING / SPEECH PROCESSIN</Domain>
	<Abstract>In OCR, a character/number to be recognized can be printed or handwritten characters/numerals. There are several approaches that deal with problem of recognition of characters/numerals depending on the type of feature extracted and different way of extracting them. Our work is focused on a technique in feature extraction and classification. The features are fed to Support Vector Machine (SVM)/Back Propagation Network (BPN) model.We are using specific SBI Cheque as an input for our application. The cheque is scanned using HP flat bed scanner. The obtained image is converted into suitable format. As we have done some basic programming in MATLAB, we prefer MATLAB based cheque processing. The work proceeds as: Binarization, Get the margins, Cutting and resizing image, Cropping cheque fields, Filtering image, Segmentation, Feature extraction, Training Network, Simulation and Classification, Display Results.The basic idea of SVM is to use linear model to implement non-linear class boundaries to some non-linear mapping of input vector into the high dimensional feature space. SVM has many advantages over BPN. The SVM is a new type of hyperplane classifier with the aim of maximizing a geometric margin of hyperplane, which is related to the error-bound of generalization. We have also worked with BPN algorithm and will finally proceed with the optimized. This subject has attracted immense research interest not only because of very challenging nature of the problem, but also because it provides the means for automatic processing of large volumes of data.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-335</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>IMPLEMENTATION OF ACOUSTIC SYSTEM</Project_Name>
	<Domain>DITAL SIGNAL PROCESSING / IMAGE PROCESSING / SPEECH PROCESSING</Domain>
	<Abstract>Low light conditions like those occurring at twilight and dusk commonly hamper visibility  by limiting the range of sight/view of road/runway etc. This frequently leads to accidents or delays. To avoid the problem, automatic methods can be proposed to enhance visibility in such conditions. Our goal is to develop a system (algorithm) which will enhance the features of an affected image. Our system will take an image from a digital camera under low light conditions which will then be processed to provide an image with enhanced features and visibility. Finally, we intend to develop a system which will allow enhanced visibility and normal functioning under any lighting conditions.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-336</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>PERFORMANCE ANALYSIS OF DIFFERENT SEGMENTATION ALGORITHMS FOR CARDIAC MRI OF LEFT VENTRICLE</Project_Name>
	<Domain>DITAL SIGNAL PROCESSING / IMAGE PROCESSING / SPEECH PROCESSING</Domain>
	<Abstract>The basic aim of the project is to do segmentation of left ventricle of the heart. Two different algorithms: 1. GVF (gradient vector flow) 2. Level set  are used for this purpose. Segmentation refers to the process of partitioning a digital image into multiple segments . The goal  is to simplify and /or change the representation of an image into something that is more meaningful and easier to analyze .During segmentation we assign a label to every pixel in an image such that pixels with the same label share certain visual characteristics. Once the segmentation of left ventricle is done , volumetric analysis of blood can be done. Amount of blood flowing during systolic and diastolic phases can be determined. With these data ejection fraction too can be calculated . All these parameters are important for diagnosing a patient’s health . Blood tests done can be used to evaluate functions of kidney and thyroid as well as cholesterol level and presence of anaemia. Presence of tumors, clots etc. in the blood can also be detected. A movie of  systolic and diastolic phases of left ventricle is taken as input. Movie is then converted into frames(number of images). Preprocessing of image is done for clarity. Proper  thresholding of image is also done. Segmentation algorithms ( GVF/Level set ) are executed on the image. Volumetric analysis is done finally using the results of segmentation.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-338</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>IMAGE PROCESSING FOR BIO MEDICAL APPLICATION</Project_Name>
	<Domain>DITAL SIGNAL PROCESSING / IMAGE PROCESSING / SPEECH PROCESSING</Domain>
	<Abstract>Karyotyping, a standard method for presenting pictures of the human chromosomes for diagnostic purposes, is a long standing, yet common technique in cytogenetics. Automating the chromosome classification process is the first step in designing an automatic karyotyping system. However, even today, karyotyping is manually performed. Here we intend to automate Karyotyping completely. Karyotyping is a common technique in cytogenetics, to classify human chromosomes into 24 classes. Karyotyping can be used to predict genetic disorders or abnormalities in pre-natal stage which may happen to occur in future generation. To classify gray scale image of chromosomes obtained during metaphase stage following steps are followed:- (1) Segmentation is performed to separate chromosomes using watershed transform due to its high accuracy as an accurate segmentation is required to automate.(2) All chromosomes within an image are straightened by calculating and analyzing the vertical and horizontal projection vectors of the binary image of the chromosome obtained at various rotation angles.(3) Optimum features like relative length, normalized density profile (d.p) and centromeric index are extracted from the image for better representation of and classification of chromosomes.(4)These features are used for training neural network classifier and final classification results were obtained and compared with the manually obtained results.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-339</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>NEURAL NETWORK BASED STOCK MARKET ANALYSIS</Project_Name>
	<Domain>DITAL SIGNAL PROCESSING / IMAGE PROCESSING / SPEECH PROCESSING</Domain>
	<Abstract>Prediction in stock market has been a hot research topic for many years. The stock market has always been an attractive area for researchers since no method has been found yet to predict the stock price behavior precisely. It carries a higher risk than any other investment area, due to its high rate of uncertainty and volatility, thus making the stock price behavior difficult to forecast. For years, conventional methods have been developed but they have succeeded partially or have completely failed to deal with the nonlinear and complex behavior of stock prices.  Artificial neural networks approach is a relatively new, active and promising field on the prediction of stock price behavior. Artificial neural networks (ANNs) are mathematical models simulating the learning and decision making processes of the human brain. Because of their nature of easy adaptation to noisy data, and solving complex and nonlinear problems, they fit into the area of stock price behavior prediction.It can be seen from a comparative analysis that the Back propagation algorithm has the ability to predict with greater accuracy than other NN algorithms, no matter which data model was used. We also further use wavelet transform.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-315</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>CAR AUTOMATION USING ‘CAN’ PROTOCOL</Project_Name>
	<Domain>COMMUNICATION SYSTEMS</Domain>
	<Abstract>In the automotive industry, embedded control has grown from stand-alone systems to highly integrated and networked control systems. By networking electro-mechanical subsystems, it becomes possible to modularize functionalities and hardware, which facilitates reuse and adds capabilities. The ECU handles the control of engine, turbofan, etc.  Combining networks and mechatronic modules makes it possible to reduce both the cabling and the number. 
 Now a days, along with the ECU the micro-controller based systems are used for many other applications like Door locking systems, Light system of cars, Fuel-level Indicators, Engine parameters detection, Hand break, etc. In many of these applications, the two or more micro-controllers are used and they need to communicate between them by some means. Also the physical distance between the micro-controllers is more as the wires are passed through the outer body of the cars. So the protocols RS232 or Mod-bus are not feasible and also not much advanced for multi-master system.The Control Area Network (CAN) protocol is an ideal choice for this application.In this project, we are using CAN protocol to communicate between micro-controllers which will analyze the parameters like Door locking system, Fuel level, Hand brake system and communicate with other micro-controller which is interfaced to Dash-board which indicates these parameters to the driver.
The idea of this project is to implement these automations especially in Indian automobiles with cost effectiveness and desired quality of performance.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-324</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>FRACTAL ANTENNA FOR BROADBAND APPLICATION</Project_Name>
	<Domain>COMMUNICATION SYSTEMS</Domain>
	<Abstract>With the advance of wireless communication systems and increasing importance of other wireless applications, widebandand low profileantennas are in great demand for both commercial and military applications. Multi-band and wideband antennas are desirable in personal communication systems, small satellite communication terminals, andother wireless applications. Wideband antennas also find applications in Unmanned Aerial Vehicles (UAVs), Counter Camouflage, Concealment and Deception(CCandD), Synthetic Aperture Radar (SAR), and Ground Moving Target Indicators (GMTI).Some of these applications also require that an antenna be embedded into the airframe structure Traditionally, a wideband antenna in the low frequency wireless bands can only be achieved with heavily loaded wire antennas, which usually means different antennas are needed for different frequency bands. Recent progress in the study of fractal antennas suggests some attractive solutions for using a single small antenna operating in several frequency bands. Many fractal element antennas use the fractal structure as a virtual combination of  capacitors and inductors. This makes the antenna so that it has many different  resonances which can be chosen and adjusted by choosing the proper fractal design.  Note that such resonances may not be related to a particular scale size of the fractal  structure: the scaling of the structure does not lead to a one-to-one scaling of resonances. This complexity arises because the current on the structure has a complex arrangement caused by the inductance and self capacitance. In general, although their effective electrical length is longer, fractal element antennas are physically smaller. Fractal element antennas are shrunken compared to conventional designs, and do not need additional components. In general the fractal dimension of a fractal antenna is a poor predictor of its performance and application..Fractal Antenna Systems is the recognized pioneer in fractal antenna technology.Based on decades of research and field experience, our patented fractal antennas enable the world’s most challenging wireless design applications in commercial and defense/intelligence sectors.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-337</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>TELEVISION BASED SHOPPING SYSTEM</Project_Name>
	<Domain>COMMUNICATION SYSTEMS</Domain>
	<Abstract>We aim at designing a shopping system where different advertisements posted on the same site, can be flashed on television screen. User can scroll through the ads while watching TV and can place an order using a remote controller. To serve the purpose using a single remote controller, we will be designing a universal remote, which operates and controls devices like television, set top box, DVD player and our shopping device that combines features of teleshopping and online shopping. The advertisements from different vendors are obtained using internet access. To display these advertisements on television, we will be using a multimedia processor. This multimedia processor will process the data obtained from internet and will convert it in to the format understandable by TV.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-108</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>TO PROVIDE SUPPORT FOR EXTENDED ATTRIBUTES IN THE YAFFS2 FILE SYSTEM</Project_Name>
	<Domain>DATABASE AND STORAGE SYSTEMS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Extended file attributes (denoted by XATTR) is a file system feature that enables users to associate computer files with metadata not interpreted by the File System, whereas regular attributes have a purpose strictly defined by the File System. Each attribute is denoted by a name and the associated data. There are four namespaces, namely system, security, trusted and user.  
 YAFFS2 File System provides various advantages over traditional Flash File Systems. It is superior to all other existing flash file systems and is currently being used as the default root file system in case of android devices.However, to be able to support advanced security features like ACL’s and SELinux, the file system should support XATTR. Additionally, some userspace applications make use of extended attributes as well, most notably id3 tags. Presently, YAFFS2 does not support XATTR. We put forward an approach to provide XATTR support in YAFFS2 so as to facilitate this and other such functionalities</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-110</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>POSIX COMPLIANT VERSIONED FUSION FS</Project_Name>
	<Domain>DATABASE AND STORAGE SYSTEMS</Domain>
	<Abstract>File system in User space (FUSE) is a loadable kernel module for Unix-like computer operating systems that allows non-privileged users to create their own file systems without editing the kernel code. FUSION is file system in user space with I/O networking. It is peer to peer file system.Our aim is to make the file system versioned so that it can store different versions of files. We are going to do versioning on updation basis. Especially in the enterprise set up, most systems used as desktops have large vacant disk storage whereas the IT department spends large sums on back up infrastructure. Instead, this tool implements a user-level file system to store encrypted, chunked data on available storage across the desktops. The tool should provide a tunable parameter for probability of recoverability of data, number of versions of the file (may be based on a directory rather than individual files).</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-143</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>PERR STORE A CO-OPERATIVE INTERNET BACKUP SCHEME</Project_Name>
	<Domain>DATABASE AND STORAGE SYSTEMS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Backing up important data has long been a standard practice. Clients traditionally rely on local storage devices to store data, but maintaining such a centralized, full backup system is expensive, especially when a large amount of data must be stored. The backup device  is both an efficiency bottleneck due to its slow bandwidth and a single point of failure, unless some redundancy (which requires additional expensive hardware) is used. In a peer-to-peer , these systems can cooperatively store each other’s data in their unused space. This eliminates the cost of backup hardware, reduces the space limitations, lessens the bandwidth bottleneck, (depending on implementation) removes the single point of failure. At the same time, this kind of system introduces new concerns about reliability and recovery, security, performance, and fairness.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-201</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>VIRTUAL TAPE LIBRARY TO SUPPORT MANDATORY SCSI STREAM COMMANDS FOR TAPE ON UNH-ISCSI</Project_Name>
	<Domain>DATABASE AND STORAGE SYSTEMS</Domain>
	<Abstract>The most important aspect of Tape Systems is their sequential nature. Tape Libraries provide both logical and physical archival processes to support data center. But traditional tape drives are slow and prone to failures. Tape drive mechanism is expensive and also restores from traditional tapes is time consuming. So to overcome the drawbacks of traditional tapes we come up with the concept of Virtual Tape Library using SCSI. A Virtual Tape Library is physically a highly intelligent optimized disk-based storage appliance. A virtual tape library (VTL) is a data storage virtualization technology used typically for backup and recovery purposes. A VTL presents a storage component (usually hard disk storage) as tape libraries or tape drives for use with existing backup software. Virtualizing the disk storage as tape allows integration of VTLs with existing backup software and existing backup and recovery processes and policies. The benefits of such virtualization include storage consolidation and faster data restore processes. Small Computer System Interface or SCSI (pronounced scuzzy), is a set of standards for physically connecting and transferring data between computers and peripheral devices. The SCSI standards define commands, protocols, and electrical and optical interfaces.We have provided tape support to UNH-iSCSI target. We have implemented SCSI stream commands (mandatory) to give tape support. This is faster and also it is very beneficial in field of storage. Also Virtual Tape is an archival storage technology that makes it possible to save data as if it were being stored on tape although it may actually be stored on hard disk or on another storage medium.Benefits of virtual tape systems include accelerated backup and recovery times, storage consolidation, efficient data management, scalability and lower operating costs.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-236</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>DISTRIBUTOR SALE ANALYSIS AND DECISION MAKING SYSTEM</Project_Name>
	<Domain>DATABASE AND STORAGE SYSTEMS</Domain>
	<Abstract>The project will handle the brand wise, manager wise, track wise and area wise database.It will also handle the database of the sale across the distributors and their various outlets.It’ll be handling Institution wise, Hotel-wise, Club-wise sale information in the database.We aim to pull the data from all the distributors everyday.
The project will be handled dynamically. For eg-The change in the area of a shop will be reflected throughout the database</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-238</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>INTELLIGENT VIRTUAL STORAGE DEVICE</Project_Name>
	<Domain>DATABASE AND STORAGE SYSTEMS</Domain>
	<Abstract>In recent years, we have observed the emergence of various storage devices of different performance characteristics in the market like hard drives, optical drives and ?ash-memory storage devices which are the most popular. When access time is considered, electronic storage devices like ?ash-memory drives have superb performance over random access patterns. We propose the design of a virtual storage device, which consists of multiple heterogeneous storage devices, with the capability in dynamic recon?guration to ?t the needs of users. A dynamic remapping mechanism is presented with a heap-based data structure to manage the moving of data among component storage devices for performance optimization. A lazy swapping method is then proposed to reduce the mapping overheads. The capability of the proposed design is evaluated with a prototype virtual storage device of a ?ash drive and a hard drive.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-112</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>PMAT- AN ORACLE FOR JAVA</Project_Name>
	<Domain>MIDDLEWARE AND DISTRIBUTED SYSTEMS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Businesses have come to rely heavily on various mission-critical Java products.Such products  suffer from availability and performance issues often when business is at its peak.Organizations mostly rely on post-facto analysis to determine the problem i.e after the problem has occurred,system administrators/developers spend a lot of time scrutinising huge logs/ Java Management Extension(JMX) statistics to find the exact cause of the problem.This solution is unacceptable in live production systems since the damage is already done.Also more time is further spent in finding the cause.We propose to solve this by developing an intelligent performance monitoring and analysis tool which provides remote,real-time monitoring of various mission-critical Java products,analyses their performance real-time and provides alerts to diagnose and predict runtime performance problems. We have chosen Java applications and distributed cache(Java-based) as our showcase examples.This tool gives an integrated view of the health of the monitored entity.It analyses the complex monitored statistics and correlates values so as to detect leading indicators of performance problems.Comprehensive alerts are then provided which tell what problem has occurred,its root cause and what could happen further.These leading indicators have been identified by us by studying the JMX statistics generated for performance-degrading situations.We concentrate on patterns for certain crucial performance problems such as resource starvation,deadlocks,memory leaks,cache thrashing,detecting inoperable cluster members,predicting the growth of cache and detecting increasing load on the cache because of backend problems. System administrators can capitalize on this knowledge and take corrective measures to prevent further degradations thus providing more control to them</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-115</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>SECURE AND ADPTIVE MIDDLEWARE FOR GROUP COMMUNICATION</Project_Name>
	<Domain>MIDDLEWARE AND DISTRIBUTED SYSTEMS</Domain>
	<Abstract>There are many existing group communication middlewares available. But these dont consider the requirement of the application running over it. The reason behind it lies in not having the knowledge of the application type parameters. These parameters such as arrival rate, departure rate, staying period, group life time and tolerance times for join and leave, are critical for meeting security requirements of the  application and for optimizing performance.So the existing group communication middlewares are neither secure nor adaptive in nature.We are designing a middleware which is both secure (forward and backward secrecy) and adaptive in nature having application class awareness (i.e. Having knowledge of application type parameters). The middleware is based on object oriented paradigms and it is modular in design to not affect the applications even if the middleware is changed.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-116</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>AGL THEME ENGINE</Project_Name>
	<Domain>MIDDLEWARE AND DISTRIBUTED SYSTEMS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Basically ThemeEngine is a library of components which allows to change visual appearance and behavior of an application with use of the powerful set of tools including visual components, convenient designers, easy-to-use non-visual components, the optimized graphic algorithms and a set of ready themes. ThemeEngine can add themes to forms, to the menu and to the elements of the management. ThemeEngine allows to use more than one theme in a application, so that you can receive a very beautiful and interesting interface.ThemeEngine includes an easy-to-use non-visual component which can automatically adjust the TColor properties of any components, depending on the loaded theme. In this way you can easily adapt any components to the new interface.
AGL Theme Engine is able to provide run-time theming for tidy widgets. It is capable of handling states like button press active/inactive. In order tidy painting does not get affected the agl_paint is called before tidy paint. The theme engine is easily pluggable to any kind of library (currently targeting tidy library).The theme engine will switch from one theme to another using css, json files and images. The themes will have capability of installing themselves at appropriate locations. Our project has come up with a combination of tidy widgets plus css and json styling. ‘css’ is used to give the look and feel to the various widgets. While ‘json’ is used to give animation. Just simple change in the css and json files will change the look without recompiling the whole program.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-118</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>ONLINE BUSINESS TO BUSINESS (B2B) TRADE PORTAL</Project_Name>
	<Domain>MIDDLEWARE AND DISTRIBUTED SYSTEMS</Domain>
	<Abstract>The major motive for this Project is that, this Project is a real time Project. The project work can be utilized for the companies to promote their products as well as sale and purchase the product of their interest. The project will be designed in such a way that will benefit both the registered and unregistered companies for promoting products online. This project will reduce the human efforts so that the dealing between companies will be speed up and they will be able to promote more products and do business in lesser time, giving better services to the companies. A user (company) can be reached to the other company easily, via website. Online B2B trade portal acts as a mediator between the users (companies). The users have to register to the site to upload the products. The admin have every right to delete (remove) the products from the site if he finds it not appropriate
At present, there are various portal sites like indiamart, alibaba etc which provides B2B facilities. But, the problem is that these sites do not provide sms facility to the user. So we are providing the sms facility to the registered user.  After receiving a sms alert, he can check his page for the mail he has received whenever he wants. This sms facility will save the user’s time and the communication between the users will speed up. Today these types of trade portals have become very influential and it is growing exponentially.</Abstract>
</Project>

<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-119</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>INTEGRATED INFORMATION MANAGER USING GOOGLE SERVICES</Project_Name>
	<Domain>MIDDLEWARE AND DISTRIBUTED SYSTEMS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Googles mission is to organize the worlds information and make it universally accessible and useful. Sometimes making information accessible requires making it available in contexts other than a web browser. Thus, Google provides APIs to let client software request information outside of a browser context.You can use the Data APIs to send queries and updates to any service that has a Data API. No integrated software exists which will access all the services at a single instance, Hence we are developing Application which will provide feature rich GUI, Easy to use and customized solution for users. Using this application access to various services will be provided to user. We are developing solution which will allow user to do the basic as well as extra and enhanced tasks which are not possible with the current system.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-122</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>KNOWLEDGE SHARING ENGINE</Project_Name>
	<Domain>MIDDLEWARE AND DISTRIBUTED SYSTEMS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Today, information is available in different forms. Information that is required is made available from different sources. One way to extract information is to query a knowledgeable person in the field related to query of the person and then obtain solution. Thus information sharing is one way to propagate the information and thereby prove your expertise to the world. Showing expertise is one way to advertise your knowledge and gain customers.Knowledge Sharing Engine is an online application which will help the expert show his expertise in his knowledgeable field and thereby propagate information. It will also help the users to obtain answers to the questions of user’s interest from an expert belonging to the category of the question. These answers can be rated by users and expert belonging to that category and thus help gain recognition. Online visibility of the expert can also help in obtaining deeper answers of the user queries and thus show his expertise thereby connecting with different people across the globe.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-125</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>SECURING DISTRIBUTED DATABASE IN CLOUD COMPUTING</Project_Name>
	<Domain>MIDDLEWARE AND DISTRIBUTED SYSTEMS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Cloud computing is the extension of grid computing. Cloud computing is a paradigm in which software/information is permanently stored in server on the internet and cached temporarily on clients (includes scanners, sensors, monitors etc.). Cloud computing helps in providing services to the client as per they demand. There are various issues related with cloud computing like ownership of data, reliability, data security etc. Data security is an important issue in cloud computing. As it involves attempt of hacking in sophisticated manner like key logging, inter dependency between public and private sector entities and among people they serve due to growth of cloud business models. So, is necessary to find out the loop holes in security of cloud computing and removing it.This paper gives the deep information about how the security is provided in the cloud by using two methods. 1. Data replication at remote location. 2. Data encryption using standard and advanced data encryption methods. This paper also tells how the cloud is build.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-130</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>GOOGLE WAVE-MS OUTLOOK INTEROP</Project_Name>
	<Domain>MIDDLEWARE AND DISTRIBUTED SYSTEMS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Email and IM are used as a platform for communication throughout the world. On, 30th September 2009, Google introduced a new communication and collaboration tool, which is considered to be the next generation of real-time communication. It has merged the email and IM services together in a single service. Outlook is the most eminent email client used in the world today. It supports only the static email retrieval and the respective operations over a mail in offline mode. As outlook is not configured to work with waves, the outlook users would be unable to use the wave technology.The Google Wave – MS Outlook interop shall provide the outlook users, the facility to work on waves. The communication shall be managed even when the users switch from online to offline mode. This shall eliminate the restriction for the user to be online for accessing the waves. The setup of the software will require a few simple steps to be followed at the time of installation. The outlook users for the wave communication can use the product once deployed.The product having a wide scope is expected to persuade the requirements of the outlook users, which would not have been possible without this interop.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-212</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>UNIGAD: A UNIVERSAL GADGET FRAMEWORK</Project_Name>
	<Domain>MIDDLEWARE AND DISTRIBUTED SYSTEMS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Application development focuses on automating business processes; hence typically any organization has multiple applications that address different business needs using intranet based web applications. On the other end we have web applications external to the organization we make use of third party applications like Google Maps, Language Translators, Financial Calculators, Stock Market Data.The aim of the Gadgets Framework is to build a web application around a generic framework which provides a high degree of user personalization and supports internal and external applications to the organization, provided those are built with industry standard common denominator for interoperability. Gadgets Framework would provide users with a set of tools to customize and organize information. Gadgets are computer programs that provide services without needing an independent application to be launched for each one, but instead run in an environment that manages multiple gadgets. The Gadgets Framework provides integrated environment to manage gadgets. The idea behind Gadgets Framework is to extend these start pages for the intranet scenarios. Organizations cannot afford their proprietary content being exposed to public internet sites. So, developing the same kind of start pages for intranet can be very useful for an organization as intranet users can then have the same pages advantage without organization content being exposed to public internet.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-215</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>MUSIC SHARING FOR ANDROID AND PC BROWSER USING TECHNIQUE OF CLOUD COMPUTING</Project_Name>
	<Domain>MIDDLEWARE AND DISTRIBUTED SYSTEMS</Domain>
	<Abstract>In today’s world music listening is the part of life. We are designing “Music Sharing Portal for Android and Browser”. This will change the way you listen music. We have two clients one which is Android OS mobile and the other one is the PC client. The application can run I mobile and browser. Generally, the music files are stored in the mobile device itself or memory card. We use new technology CLOUD COMPUTING. The file is kept somewhere on the cloud which can run on a client. The music file can be played on the mobile which supports Android OS, and a PC browser which can run in desktop OS installed. User will able to do: 1.Listen music 2.Create Play list 3.Share Music File 4.Upload Media file This application is being developed for Android based mobiles.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-218</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>TO DEVELOP AN EASY-TO-INTEGRATE AUTHENTICATION PLUG-IN THAT CAN BE USED FOR WEB DEVELOPMENT. IT USES THE CONCEPT OF OPENID IDENTITY FOR END USER VERIFICATION</Project_Name>
	<Domain>MIDDLEWARE AND DISTRIBUTED SYSTEMS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Authentication module is a very important module in case of web development. Any website maintains a database of valid users that are allowed to use the resources provided by the same. Instead of authenticating users by maintaining their accounts there is a method by which the website can rely on Identity Providers like Google, Yahoo, IBM, AOL, etc. for providing access privileges to its users. This concept of using a single identity for authentication of users is called OpenID.   OpenID authentication is supported by a number of websites. However, they have to develop their own separate authentication module for the same. This plug-in, is a ready-to-use authentication module. Web developers that are using Ruby on Rails framework can easily integrate it in their application. On the part of end users, it will save the effort of keeping a track of multiple identities and use the same digital identities on websites.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-224</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>WEB BASED AUTOMATED PATCH PROPAGATION TOOL</Project_Name>
	<Domain>MIDDLEWARE AND DISTRIBUTED SYSTEMS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Patch propagation tool is a web based application for applying patches to the open source code. Patches comes in the form of textual differences between the original and modified versions of source code. Source code and patches exist at central repository and client can request to the server for applying patches. This tool also helps in managing the various versions of the source code so created. As it is web based application it is very much helpful in a heterogeneous environment wherein various developers working on a project can view and modify code from their respective workstations. User authentication is required before he accesses the application and this provides the required security. It does not allow more than one client to modify the source code at a time. Report is generated whenever a client modifies the source code and history of previous modifications is also stored so that one can view the status before applying patch.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-309</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>IMPLEMENT ALGORITHM FOR CLOUD COMPUTING WHICH WILL INSURE EFFICIENT LOAD DISTRIBUTION</Project_Name>
	<Domain>MIDDLEWARE AND DISTRIBUTED SYSTEMS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Cloud computing is new approach towards computing. This approach is totally different than conventional approach where person has to buy computing Hardware or Software or platform. In this approach person can ask cloud vendors to allocate him a particular Hardware configuration or Software or even platform, user will only be paying for what he ahs used on rent basis in this way user does not have to spend lot amount of money for simpler tasks also it avoids hassles related to Software or Hardware upgrade Cloud vendors which ill be providing computing resources will provide these services over internet Then these requests will be transferred to particular machine depending upon type of request traditionally round robin is used for this task however but round robin can create problems when a resource savvy application is in queue and all servers are mid occupied.So in our project we will replace RR algorithm with our load distribution algorithm which will have an ascending list of servers and all requests will be given to the server which least capable for providing service.Least capable server will be chosen out of ascending list maintained throughout according to their current capability.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-113</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>DOCUMENT CLUSTERING USING WORDNET SEMANTIC DICTIONARY</Project_Name>
	<Domain>DATA MINING</Domain>
	<Abstract>Text document clustering can greatly simplify browsing large collections of documents by reorganizing them into a smaller number of manageable clusters. Algorithms to solve this task exist; however, the algorithms are only as good as the data they work on.  Problems include ambiguity and synonymy, the former allowing for erroneous groupings and the latter causing similarities between documents to go unnoticed. Hence we proposed to use the Wordnet semantic dictionary in the document clustering which will give more specific semantic relations for grouping the text documents. So that the documents from one cluster have high similarity in comparison to another .As the preprocessing is also important as choice of clustering algorithm because  algorithm can only be as good as the data it works on. Hence the use of Wordnet will solve the problem of ambiguity and will increase the efficiency of clustering.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-114</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>TAG BASED CLUSTERING OF YAHOO SEARCH RESULTS</Project_Name>
	<Domain>INFORMATION RETRIEVAL</Domain>
	<Abstract>The exponential growth in Web sites is making it increasingly difficult to extract useful information on the Internet using existing search engines. The traditional search engines like Yahoo present results as an extensive list of links to Web pages. Moreover, their ranking algorithms often do not reflect individual user preferences. Social bookmarking is an emerging type of a Web service that helps users share, classify, and discover interesting resources using tags as a simple, flexible way to categorize resources. These tags are individual contributions of bookmarking users which reflects their preferences. We are extending the search capabilities of search engine by providing results that have been tagged by others. The premise is that people who tag sites are more accurate at identifying the most valuable Web resources. Therefore we propose a web application which is on the similar lines of a web search engine. This web application provides tag based clustering on Yahoo search results.This application uses Yahoo APIs to retrieve Yahoo search results. Then it will further process these results to get the related tags from Delicious. The responses from search engines to a particular query can be broadly grouped into meaningful categories. Clustering algorithms attempt to group results together based on tags provided by users for those results. This can help users both in locating interesting documents more easily and in getting an overview of the retrieved document set.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-104</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>TO DESIGN A TEST CASE MANAGEMENT AND REPORTING TOOL</Project_Name>
	<Domain>QA AND TESTING</Domain>
	<Abstract>There are various phases of a software development. Starting from Requirements gathering to Deployment phase. The Software testing is the vital stage prior to Deployment. As well said :”The bug free software counts”. Hence it’s very important to test whatever one has coded so as to test whether that code is really feasible or not .Currently in the TIBCO they are using some of the third party software for their internal working to be more precise for testing the new software products they develop. So, they are requiring the something that will save their cost on the third party product in the form of monetary and memory space also.Thus we are intending to design the test case management and reporting tool. Basically this tool is proposed to work on all the OS platforms and will give the comparative results for the corresponding test cases for various languages. The concerned tool will be saving the time of an execution as well as memory space required. Also not only the priceless time will be saved but also cost will be reduced which is also an important aspect. This tool also going to support the various platforms such as linux,   macintosh , windows, etc.So this tool will drastically lower down the need of the memory and the cost in terms of the monetary. And it will also support the various platforms. The comparative reports are to be shown in the form of graphs.Also the study of the Cobertura code coverage is to be done in an addition.This tool will tell the percentage of the lines covered and analyse the coverage</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>IM-142</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>AUTOMATION OF OS SECURITY AUDITS FOR WINDOWS SERVER 2003</Project_Name>
	<Domain>SECURITY</Domain>
	<Abstract>The security audit of server hardening contains a listing of the status for the various agreed upon settings for the system. These include registry values, system policies, group policies, CPU utilization, resource usage etc.Presently, the process is a manual task which is performed on a quarterly basis. A system to automate the checks and generate the audit report can be put in place to improve efficiency.The settings of a system can change due to several reasons, including -1. Manual change to settings to run any service 2.Installation of a system patch. The changes may be unintentional but still pose a security vulnerability risk. An automated audit tool will ensure that the exposed vulnerability doesn’t exist for a long period, thus reducing any possible security threats. If automated, the checks can be performed every 2-3 days instead of on a quarterly basis. The auditing will be done during periods of low activity and a concurrent audit report generated. This helps improve the security of the system and reduces wastage of man-hours which can be utilized for better productivity. The proposed system also keeps a record of the system state going back up to 6 months which can help track effect of patches and updates.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-013</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>BLUE NET</Project_Name>
	<Domain>NETWORKING</Domain>
	<Abstract>To design a Prototype and Topology based on Bluetooth Technology to overcome the shortcomings of current Prototypes present for Bluetooth and also to overcome the Shortcomings of the Current Bluetooth Hardware using Software Techniques. Challenges to basic Bluetooth protocol and  solutions implemented for it :The basic Bluetooth protocol structure is half duplex, where in BlueNet we are making it full duplex using FCFS scheduling algorithm.For making the data transfer Crash Resistant we are using the concepts of TCP protocol.For providing security to the data to be transmitted we are using symmetric encryption algorithm and dynamic key generation.Using BlueNet we can transfer the file to more than one Bluetooth devices at a time.We are designing the topologies to advice for Maximum Coverage using Minimum amount of Dongles.\In basic Bluetooth Protocol for transferring data from one slave to other slave which are lying in different piconet must be transferred through the masters of both piconets where we are redesigning the protocol in such a way that data can be transferred from one slave to other slave without master intervention.The basic Bluetooth protocol structure is master and topology dependent we are removing these limitations in BlueNet.In BlueNet we are providing the facility for congestion control by modifying the original Leaky Bucket Technique in which if the amount of incoming data exceeds the capacity of the Queue then the access of data is rejected. So to overcome this problem BlueNet implements a protocol of alternate path search. This protocol searches for all the neighboring nodes to see if some other node is free and reroutes the data from alternate path.In BlueNet we are providing the facility of finding the shortest path between any two nodes using the shortest path algorithm.In BlueNet system sustainability does not depend on any single dongle.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-078</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>VIRTUAL SOCIAL NETWORKING WEBSITE</Project_Name>
	<Domain>NETWORKING</Domain>
	<Abstract>The aim of the project is to create an interactive Virtual world consisting of web information portal. Our website is aimed towards the people who are interested in social networking, chatting, online shopping, trying out products online (clothes, sunglasses etc.) and so our website will be a medium through which the user will be able to achieve the above features. The Virtual world will contain replicas of the real world buildings like Shopping malls, Theatres, Parks, Café Shops, etc. These virtual places will contain the ads of new products, Discount offers which are currently going on in the real world. The user can create his/her Avatar in the virtual world. The avatar is the self image in virtual reality. The Users avatar can try the products online like Sunglasses, Clothes, Shoes, bags, jewelry etc in virtual world. All the products will be the actual replica of the real world products.  The interface will be a GUI, which will contain a virtual world. The user will select the virtual place by clicking on it and enter into the selected virtual place. The user’s Avatar will explore the virtual place, make friends, and chat with other online user Avatars.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-173</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>DEVICE INDEPENDENT MODELING</Project_Name>
	<Domain>NETWORKING</Domain>
	<Abstract>In this project we are categorizing the display devices such as mobiles, monitors etc. in three profiles as low and high. Low profile devices are the ones which have lower color depth or lower resolution or all or some of them and higher profile devices are the ones which have higher resolution and color depth. We are going to have a project which would model the web pages according to different profiles and screen size and orientation in contrast to what is being done currently that is having different web pages for every type of profile.Our project mainly stresses on building software that should be installed on a proxy server. Every incoming request from the client for accessing web pages should first pass through our software before going to the proxy server so that the required user string can be captured by DIM. Again the response document (i.e., HTML document of requested web page) is the input of DIM. As a result, a final XML document is modeled using the information in user string and incoming HTML document.The advantage of this software is the net users would no more be constrained by the device capability restrictions. It would not be necessary to store statically designed web pages for each and every device saving memory on web servers. It would also save designing and developing time needed to develop separate web pages for each and every device.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-354</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>DISTRIBUTED CACHING IN SCALA</Project_Name>
	<Domain>NETWORKING</Domain>
	<Abstract>This project aims at developing a pure generic distributed caching system for a client server model for increasing the cache memory of the complete system, which is limited to at most 3 GB. The system includes features for dynamic addition and deletion of processors (cache servers) to scale and meet the requirement of the administrator. The system will use 1 hop request management system to transfer data between client and server in a more speedy and error free way. Mainly the system will eradicate the most common problem of bottle neck by distributing the requests from clients which were initially directed to a single server to more than 1 server. The complete system is such that the data in one computer is not replicated or duplicated in any other computer making it a pure distributed system. The system is build such that all the computers in the system are independent of each other and failure of any computer won’t bring the system to a stand still.  The system distributes the work load from 1 computer to more than 1 computer and still gives a perspective to the user as a single system is being used. It can easily be scaled as per requirements and available resources to suit the needs of the administrator.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-502</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>RAPS DETECTION AND PREVENTION IN WIRELESS NETWORK USING HIDDEN MARKOV MODEL</Project_Name>
	<Domain>NETWORKING</Domain>
	<Abstract>One of the most challenging security concerns for network administrators is the presence of rogue access points. In this project, we propose a statistical based approach to detect rogue access points using a Hidden Markov Model applied to passively measure packet-header data collected at a gateway router. Our approach utilizes variations in packet inter-arrival time to differentiate between authorized access points and rouge access points. We designed and developed our Hidden Markov Model by analyzing Denial of Service attacks and the traffic characteristics of 802.11 based Wireless Local Area Networks. Experimental validations demonstrate the effectiveness of our approach. Our trained Hidden Markov Model can detect the presence of a Rogue Access Point promptly within one second with extreme accuracy (very low false positive and false negative ratios are obtained). The success of our approach lies in the fact that it leverages knowledge about the behavior of the traffic characteristics of 802.11 based WLANs and properties of Denial of Service attacks. Our approach is scalable and non-intrusive, requiring little deployment cost and effort, and is easy to manage and maintain.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-174</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>ALARM THE COMPLETE SYSTEM ARMOUR</Project_Name>
	<Domain>NETWORK AND INFORMATION SYSTEM SECURITY</Domain>
	<Abstract>Computer virus….. System failure.These words bring to mind a computer system brought to its knees that’s data corrupted and time wasted. Is this an accurate picture? We hear arguments against investing in virus protection: Viruses are mythical. Your chances of getting hit by one are pretty often’. Others tell us software’s are a necessary for protection.’ Viruses can cost us a lot of money. It’s better safe than to be sorry.’ So, what are we to believe?Apart from this, Information in the form of data in today’s technical era is ultimately the backbone of the world of computers. But, it is a fact of grief that mankind even in its several attempts has failed to protect it from the various threats. Basically, there should be an unbreakable solution to protect the system.The main reason for choosing this project is to understand the system and unveil and exploit every aspect of it and to get to the core at the quest of the problem in hand being encountered in daily life in computers world, with respect to the threats posed to it and at the same time not neglecting the security of the security system itself.To counter the various possible threats like one that reduce CPU utilization, infect system files and resources, system database, etc., software that provides one in all solution to protect from the same, “ALARM – The Complete System Armour”, automatically derives and deploys a prescription for detecting and removing the threats.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-353</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>GENERALIZED FRAMEWORK FOR SECURED COMMUNICATION</Project_Name>
	<Domain>NETWORK AND INFORMATION SYSTEM SECURITY</Domain>
	<Abstract>The project aims at developing a generalized framework for secured communication that would best suit the requirements of the employees working in an organization. It helps in serving the internal needs of the business activities. The framework allows Company Administrator to customize the System as per requirements without any coding customization.  The framework will have two instances, server and client. At the server end the administrator will customize following parameters according to his Organizations requirement. 1.Hierarchy of levels. 2.Task management (assigned tasks). 3.Global messages (soft notice board).  4.Chat (confidential). 5.Offline messages. 6.Reminders. 7.Holidays. 8.ISO rules and regulations. 9.Employee ratings. 10.Keep track of work progress.At client end, the client can only access details as per his designation. The communication between server and client will take place over VPN and SHA512. VPN (Virtual private network): We are going to use virtual private network setup along with   leased lines provided by BSNL or MTNL for connectivity. VPN is basically used for connecting different branches of the company if any.SHA 512: Secure hash algorithm is used for providing double encryption.The need for using SHA along with VPN is that, VPN protocols can be easily hacked but if we provide SHA 512 we can provide double encryption i.e. if any person tries to hack any information, he will only get the encrypted  data.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-453</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>BIOMETRIC CRYPTOSYSTEM USING FUZZY VAULT FOR FINGERPRINTS</Project_Name>
	<Domain>NETWORK AND INFORMATION SYSTEM SECURITY</Domain>
	<Abstract>Security of information is becoming a major issue in todays era. Cryptographic systems have been widely used in many information security applications. One of the main challenges that these systems have been facing is how to protect secret keys from attackers. Current cryptographic algorithms e.g., Advanced Encryption Standard, Data Encryption Standard, RSA have a very high proven security but they suffer from the key management problem. As a solution, Fuzzy Vault which is the merger of biometrics and cryptography is proposed. It is used effectively to protect secret keys and to release them only when legitimate users enter their biometric data. The Fuzzy Vault binds the fingerprint features with the secret key.In this system, during encryption, the user provides his secret key along with the fingerprint. For decryption only the fingerprint is required hence the user need not remember the key. The key is secured using the fingerprints which is released on fingerprint match for decryption. The greatest advantage of this project is that the vault can be stored separately which adds greater security. Also separate database is not required. Even if the vault is stolen, it is very difficult to reveal the key due to its fuzzy nature. Finite Field Arithmetic and Lagrange Interpolation are the mathematical parts used. This solution keeps the AES intact but solves its key management problem. This software piece can be used to encrypt any file and to secure its secret key. This is an innovative system and has not been implemented so far.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-852</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>DATA SKY SPOOL</Project_Name>
	<Domain>NETWORK AND INFORMATION SYSTEM SECURITY</Domain>
	<Abstract>Now a day’s data security problem in every industry is increasing. Every industry or organization has its own confidential data which can be fully protected from logical and physical crashes.“Data Sky Spool” software provides security and data backup to user by using different web servers. This software removes the drawbacks of logical and physical crashes. Hence in order to have better and secured organizational structure. Data Sky Spool is better software providing high security for any confidential information. Example of Data Sky Spool application includes information fields such as Banking System, various industries, Military Systems, etc.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-855</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>PRIVACY PRESERVING SEARCHES ON ENCRYPTED DATA ON A REMOTE SYSTEM</Project_Name>
	<Domain>NETWORK AND INFORMATION SYSTEM SECURITY</Domain>
	<Abstract>Many users want to store their private data at a remote system and yet want to maintain its privacy. The privacy of the server as well as the client must also be maintained. User will not want the server to access his files and hence the data is kept in an encrypted format at the server. The user later wants to retrieve files based on a keyword search. That is, user wants to retrieve files containing (or indexed by) some keyword. If the files are encrypted, there is no straight forward way for server to do keyword search unless user is willing to leak the decryption key. A trivial solution that preserves the security of users files is to have server send all the encrypted files back to him. This may not be a feasible solution if user is using mobile devices with limited bandwidth and storage space. An additional complication is that user may naturally also want to keep secret the keyword that he is interested in as well.The solution to this problem utilizes the notion of a keyword index, which is created by user. The keyword index associates each keyword with its associated files. All keyword searches by user are based on this index. In this framework user can have complete control over what words are keywords and which keywords are associated with which files, a power that can be useful for many applications. No public-key cryptosystem is required in these schemes.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-030</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>GET MY PC ON PHONE</Project_Name>
	<Domain>WIRELESS AND MOBILE COMMUNICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Data entering and leaving the mobile phone is encapsulated in a wireless (Bluetooth / Wi-Fi) connection. The bridge to the Internet is provided by a Wi-Fi access point. The system is compatible with current Wi-Fi standards using TCP/IP for data and signalling transmission. Wi-Fi was selected because it is increasingly available in mobile telephones. Since an important goal was to implement a prototype that runs on a broad spectrum of devices, Java was chosen to be the target platform for the mobile phone. Java is largely supported by mobile devices widely used in industry and provides a native java application programming interface.The Wireless access point acts as a bridge between the wireless smart phone and the Internet. The first important role of the access point is to advertise to passing-by mobile phones the service it provides. A dynamic network of wireless devices may browse remote devices for their services, and properties, allowing for better network dynamism and re placing the need for a central repository. Each client application will communicate with the application server which resides normally out of the firewall network in an organization. We have both client applications i.e. for smart phone as well as for desktop machine that is in the protected network conditions. An application server will listen for the communication requests from the client application and processes accordingly. As the application server knows the exact IP addresses of each client, so it can initiate the communication between these clients.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-063</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>WI-SENSE (A WIRELESS AGRICULTURE MONITOTRING SYSTEM)</Project_Name>
	<Domain>WIRELESS AND MOBILE COMMUNICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Advances in wireless personal area networks have made the practical deployment of various services possible, which until a few years ago was considered extremely costly or labor intensive. We are building such a wireless sensor network for precision agriculture where real time data of the climatological and other environmental properties are sensed and relayed to a centrally located base station. The architecture comprises of three distinct sections – (a) the sensor-nodes (b) the wireless network and (c) the actuation components. The sensors are selected based on the properties suited for the most common crops and we identify six such attributes. The sensor network is based on the IEEE-802.15.4 standard.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-072</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>ALZHEIMER AID USING RFID</Project_Name>
	<Domain>WIRELESS AND MOBILE COMMUNICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>In this project, we’ll be implementing a monitoring system for assisting people suffering from alzheimer’s disease. The objective of this system is to assist these patients to walk around independently and safely in transportation centers by providing visual guidance on their current location and navigation information on how to move to a particular location.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-098</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>MMS BASED SECURITY SYSTEM</Project_Name>
	<Domain>WIRELESS AND MOBILE COMMUNICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Security is prime concern in our day – to – day life. Everyone wants to be secure to the extent possible. An access control system forms a vital link in a security chain. The system comprises of a small electronic unit with a numeric keypad, LCD Display which is fixed outside the entrance door. When a person enters the pre determined number (password) via the keypad and if the entered password is correct then the relay operates for a limited time to trigger the stepper motor. This way the door gets open. If the entered password is incorrect the door remains closed.If in any case, somebody succeeds to break this security and opens the door then we have another security system installed to provide further security.This system is installed inside the room and has Cell phone connection with the user or the owner of that place. This stage keeps a watch over any unauthorized movement inside the room. If there is any movement in the room, it is sensed by PIR sensor. The camera is triggered by this output. The recording of images is done with use of DVR card and saved on the hard disk of computer. Using the software developed; image is read from the hard disk and loaded on server mobile. From server mobile it is sent to receiver mobile of user. This whole process takes place in real time. Thus the user gets video of the happenings in the system area.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>C0-101</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>WEB BASED HOME AUTOMATION</Project_Name>
	<Domain>WIRELESS AND MOBILE COMMUNICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Normally in today’s world people still do some of the movement in their life to control their device. Due to this it consumes time to get to that particular device and making it on or off. This system presents the design and implementation of an automation system that can monitor and control home appliances via the World Wide Web. The design is based on a standalone embedded system board integrated into a PC-based server at home. The home appliances are connected to the input/output ports of the embedded system board and their status are passed to the server. The home appliances can be monitored and controlled locally via the embedded system board, or remotely through a Web browser from anywhere in the world provided that an Internet access is available. The system is scalable and allows multi-vendor appliances to be added with no major changes to its core. Password protection is used to block unauthorized users from accessing the appliances at home. If the Internet connection is down or the server is not up, the embedded system board still can control and operate the appliances locally.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-206</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>MUSIC ON DEMAND – A SREAMING APPLICATION FOR ANDROID</Project_Name>
	<Domain>WIRELESS AND MOBILE COMMUNICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Music On Demand is dedicated to making it easier for people to access and enjoy their digital music whenever and wherever they want. Our software connects people directly with their content, without the hassles of synching or uploading all their files. Music On Demands users can also share their personal media with family and close friends in a private, secure group.If you have loads of music on your computers hard drive, the phones storage can be limiting, unless you dont mind constantly rotating music on and off your Android phone. The incredibly useful this app lets you stream your songs from your Linux-based Rhythmbox to your Android phone. You can also stream from friends libraries or share your music, and the app displays artist bios.Music from shared libraries is streamed on demand in real time. MOD leverages the implementation of DAAP. RhythmBox shares the music library on LAN and we tunnel the DAAP packets over Internet to the servers shared library.Android being the next generation phone MOD is a promising way to stream music on it without actually utilizing the disk space. Once the application is installed and configured, just leave your system running and hit the road. When you run the application, youll be able to browse your entire desktop music library by album, artist, genre, or song. Tap what you want and presto: the music plays, complete with album art and it single-handedly justifies the use of the application.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-262</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>XML-BASED CHANNEL INTERFACE FOR MOBILE APPLICATION WITH RSS 2.0 AND ATOM SYNDICATION</Project_Name>
	<Domain>WIRELESS AND MOBILE COMMUNICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>The application aims at developing Really Simple Syndication (RSS) reader software meant to be used for the mobile phones. The RSS reader is a J2ME (Java) application for cell phones/mobiles and is able to read most RSS servers/feed versions. Basically, RSS and Atom are file formats designed for sharing headlines, logs and news. A RSS document includes full or summarized text, plus metadata such as publishing dates and authorship. Web feeds benefit publishers by letting them syndicate content automatically. They benefit readers who want to subscribe to timely updates from favored websites or to aggregate feeds from many sites into one place. RSS feeds can be read using the RSS reader software, which can be web-based, desktop-based, or mobile-device-based. A standardized XML file format allows the information to be published once and viewed by many different programs. The RSS reader checks the users subscribed feeds regularly for new work, downloads any updates that it finds, and provides a user interface to monitor and read the feeds. To enable the use of this application on the mobile phones, some communication method is required between the computer and the phone to be working and copying the required jar file from the system onto the mobile device. This application is extended 
to run on RIM’s Blackberry smart phones. </Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-509</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>MOBILE SSH</Project_Name>
	<Domain>WIRELESS AND MOBILE COMMUNICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>In recent years, secure communication has been broadly  applied to daily network transactions. For example, many commercial companies employ the SSL/TLS secure tunnel technique  in stock trading systems, Internet phones, and Internet banking systems. Since data transferred in secure tunnels are protected by cryptography techniques, they are free from eavesdropping by malicious users. Among these secure channel technologies, SSH is a famous example to provide secure communication channels. With SSH, users login to servers without threats of information leakage.SSH (secure shell) is a very popular secure communication application. Users can remotely login to servers through SSH channels with security protection. However, since the SSH protocol lacks mobility management support, an SSH session can be easily broken while the wireless device roams around.  we propose a mobile SSH protocol which employs an application-layer handover mechanism. We have implemented the proposed SSH protocol in OpenSSH and Putty. With the proposed protocol, the mobile users can switch from one wireless network to another without terminating their SSH sessions.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-012</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>COLOR BASED OBJECT SORTING SYSTEM</Project_Name>
	<Domain>INTELLIGENT SYSTEMS</Domain>
	<Abstract>To sort three different colored objects (red,blue,green) for real time application using image processing.The system will firstly capture the image of the object placed on the conveyor belt and then put them into respective containers according to their color. As shown in the block diagram, a web camera having 1.3Megapixel resolution will capture an image of an object. This webcam is interfaced with the PC.After image processing is done, the color of  the object (red or blue or green) is detected. This finishes image processing part.Parallel port is used for driving external hardware.The object sorting model:-	Itconsists of conveyor belt on which objects to be sorted are placed. This assembly also consists of one cylindrical container having four slots made for each color i.e red, green, blue and fourth for color other than these three.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-401</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>FINGER-KNUCKLE JOINT RECOGNITION FOR PERSON IDENTIFICATION</Project_Name>
	<Domain>INTELLIGENT SYSTEMS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Our aim is to develop software for Finger-Knuckle joint recognition for identification which falls in the category of Biometrics. This project investigates a new biometric system based on texture of the hand knuckles. The texture pattern produced by the finger knuckle bending is highly unique and makes the surface a distinctive biometric identifier. The finger back surface images from each of the users are used to extract scale, translation and rotational invariant knuckle images. Like finger print, iris, the image-pattern formation from finger-knuckle bending is highly unique and thus makes this surface a distinctive biometric identifier. The human fingers are capable of bending forward and are resistant to backward motion which results in formation more wrinkles on dorsal i.e. opposite side of palm. Hence, this can be used for person identification.  The advantages of employing finger-knuckle imaging are numerous. First, the finger geometry can be acquired simultaneously from the same image and employed to improve the systems performance and second, it helps to make the system touch less and third, there will be no need to carry the ID cards. This can be achieved with the help of one VGA or High Resolution Camera that will be used to capture the wrinkle formation. This image will be then compared with the image stored in the database. After the analysis if they match, then the person is identified. So, our motive is to develop an efficient and less expensive technology that can be employed in day today life.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-403</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>ADSCON-ADAPTIVE SPEED CONTROL SYSTEM FOR AUTOMOBILES</Project_Name>
	<Domain>INTELLIGENT SYSTEMS</Domain>
	<Abstract>In recent years the use of vehicles has increased tremendously, new technologies are being included in it to increase the convenience and comfort of the users. One such attempt is to make the user completely “hands free” where the user is expected only to monitor the working of the system without actually touching the pedals or the steering.Adaptive speed control system allows setting of safe distance between a vehicle and the vehicle ahead of it, as well as maximum speed. One has to simply have to activate the ADSCON mode and monitor the system. When a slower moving vehicle comes in front, the system automatically slows down and maintains the pre-set following distance. Adaptive speed control system automatically adjusts vehicle speed and distance to a preceding vehicle, thus enhancing driver comfort.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-422</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>DESIGN PATTERN ANALYSIS USING AST FOR JAVA SOURCE CODE</Project_Name>
	<Domain>INTELLIGENT SYSTEMS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Given a JAVA source code we have to analyze the AST to determine the design patterns used	in it. The idea behind design patterns is simple-to catalogue common interactions with objects that programmers have frequently found useful or solutions to common problems. The purpose of the project is to design an Eclipse Plug-In to automatically recognize the design patterns used in any given java source code. This would help developers to automatically generate J-Units and document their code. A design pattern is a general reusable solution to a commonly occurring problem in software design. A design pattern is not a finished design that can be transformed directly into code. It is a description or template for how to solve a problem that can be used in many different situations. GoF (Gang of Four) Design Patterns is a catalogue of 23 generally useful patterns for writing object-oriented software. They are originally grouped into the categories Creational patterns, Structural patterns, and Behavioural patterns.In computer science, an abstract syntax tree (AST), or just syntax tree, is a tree representation of the abstract (simplified) syntactic structure of source code written in a certain programming language. The syntax is abstract in the sense that it does not represent every detail that appears in the real syntax. The tool generates AST using built-in libraries for each class in an application. The tool uses the syntax trees generated to determine the design patterns used.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-854</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>PREDICTING WWW SURFING USING MULTIPLE EVIDENCE COMBINATION</Project_Name>
	<Domain>INTELLIGENT SYSTEMS</Domain>
	<Abstract>One of the basic data mining techniques is Prediction. This technique can be applied to web usage mining for finding the patterns and make prediction. The basic aim of project is to build a model that will determine the next link of choice of a user while surfing on the NET. Our approach is to combine the two classification techniques namely, Markov model and Support Vector machine (SVM) using the Dempster’s rule. This hybrid model overcomes the inability of the Markov model in predicting the unseen data as well as overcoming the problem of multi classification in the case of SVM, especially when dealing with large number of classes. We apply feature extraction to increase the power of discrimination of SVM. The model also provides the recommendations to web user so that their surfing gets sophisticated.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-111</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>ROUND TRIP ENGINEERING TOOLFOR JAVASCRIPT</Project_Name>
	<Domain>USER APPLICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Our project allows users to generate code from UML diagrams and vice-versa, more specifically to generate UML diagrams from code in JavaScript. JavaScript is a commonly used scripting language. Our tool, which uses JavaScript, will be widely used in the development of advanced web-based applications. We are providing the capability to quickly generate source code in JavaScript from a given UML diagram. This will dramatically reduce the implementation time in the project life-cycle. We are designing a tool to facilitate forward and reverse engineering. Forward engineering means that the user creates UML diagrams. The UML diagrams have some connoted model data. The UML tool derives required information from the diagrams in XML format. This XML is parsed and information is stored in the form of tokens. These tokens will be substituted in the approriate template to generate the code stub. Reverse engineering means that the user inputs a JavaScript code.The UML tool derives required information from the code in XML format. This XML is used to generate corresponding graphical UML diagrams[3].Our tool will be a plug-in on Eclipse platform. We will be using the Violet, an Eclipse plug-in for drawing UML diagrams. The templates will be generated using Velocity Templating Language.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-405</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>INTELLIGENT HOME</Project_Name>
	<Domain>USER APPLICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>The main aim of the system is to investigate a cost effective solution that will provide a control over selected home appliances remotely and this is efficiently brought into practical by our ‘Intelligent Home Project system’. This project includes three basic modules such as Voice controlling via Microphone, SMS controlling via cell phones and face detection security via webcam. The voice control module which recognizes the user’s voice commands is mainly implemented using Microsoft SDK5.1. The SMS control module which recognizes the sent message of user from mobile phones is implemented using AXMS tool. The face comparison done with the help of webcam is implemented by using Face recognition algorithm in MATLAB.Generally there are many home controlling products available in the market. In many other countries, such product is common in every field such as industries, call centers, offices and many other important places. But in India, as the standard of living of average Indian people is not enough economical, such product is purchased by only few economically stable n rich peoples. But as India is developing country, we must try to overcome such economic problems.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-018</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>INDUSTRIAL DATA ACQUISITION SYSTEM</Project_Name>
	<Domain>USER APPLICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>The project is basically an Industrial Data Acquisition System. A Data Acquisition System is a system which includes capturing data from industrial instruments for monitoring purpose.  There is a LAN where there is a computer (master) and some industrial instruments like temperature sensors, pressure controllers, level checker which would be the slaves. Around 31 different instruments would be there as slaves. Each instrument has a unique IP address. The computer and the instruments are connected in the LAN. Using the software we will be able to monitor and control the instruments without actually having to go to each instrument to take the readings.The software will function as follows:The software will basically be running as a background application. It will be continuously monitoring the different instruments. If any reading is out of bound it will be immediately highlighted to the user. The user can even change the values of the instruments e.g. say on just a button click from your computer you will be able to reduce the set point of a boiler say from 150 to 145.Continuously packets would be sent and then the instruments will respond accordingly and that value will be fetched by the software and will be displayed to the user. Here when the command will be sent there is a specific format according to the protocol. The protocol used is similar  to the MODBUS ASCII protocol with some minor differences. Then the software will check whether the command received is from the specific instrument or not. So this will guarantee data integrity and will monitor any errors in the commands.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-024</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>UI FRAMEWORK FOR WEB AND DESKTOP APPLICATION.</Project_Name>
	<Domain>USER APPLICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>The existing system involves programming of individual codes for developing the same application on a desktop system and a web based system. This approach exhibits problems such as: platform dependency, disparity in resolution and GUI.The project involves development of a single source code which will enable one to deploy the same application to both. This approach, make use of three main modules- Dispatcher: Identify the button clicked on the UI and dispatch corresponding click action to the   dispatch receiver.Dispatch Receiver: Handle the received click action and give the corresponding response to the     normal code.Normal Code: It will execute the action and will return the result to the browser via the same path in backward direction. Information is accessed directly from here while working on the desktop side.The above said problem statement is being implemented using the C++ QT technology. QT framework inherently provides the feature for creating frameworks that are operating system and browser independent.Event handling in QT: The project involves handling of events (signals) using event handlers   (slots). The signals and slots mechanism is type safe: The signature of a signal must match the signature of the receiving slot. The business logic for the existing system was distributed over the server as well as client side. However, now the business logic has been shifted to the server side alone as per client specification. This business logic of the client – server model is confidential.A few APIs would be rendered, for use in the project.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-040</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>POWERPOINT SWIFFOR</Project_Name>
	<Domain>USER APPLICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>PowerPoint Swiffor is a tool which converts PowerPoint Presentations into its corresponding SWF (Shockwave Flash) representation. The tool is intended to be used with a very popular flash based virtual classroom solution for sharing presentations.The key points addressed by this tool are: speed of conversion, accuracy, the quality of output and size of output. Microsoft PowerPoint 2007 object library is used for extracting information from a PPT.Converting each slide into SWF file.Write SWF file directly to remove any extra dependency on any other compiler.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-079</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>DEVELOPMENT OF QT BASED APPLICATIONS ON DESKTOP AND PORTING ONE OF THE APPLICATIONS ON NOKIA’S S60 PLATFORM BASED DEVICE.</Project_Name>
	<Domain>USER APPLICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>This document aims at defining the overall software requirements for ‘Qt based Applications’ such as Web Browser’ and ‘Media Player’ and porting one of the applications on Nokia’s S60 platform based device.Qt is a powerful C++ cross-platform application development framework. With the Qt port to Symbian, Nokia is broadening their embedded offering. Qt brings an elegant and intuitive C++ development tool to the S60 platform, improving the ability to develop richer user experiences on the platform, and making S60 on Symbian OS even more attractive for developers to target with their applications and services. Web browser is the first Qt based application that combines a minimal design with sophisticated technology to make the web faster, safer, and easier. The web browser will have all the standard features like History, Address field, Back andForward Button, Maximize Button, Minimize Button, Restore Button, Reload or Refresh Button, Window Title, Bookmarks. There are Special Features like Private Browsing Mode, Wikipedia Encyclopedia, Weather updates, RSS Feed  also Rich GUI  Features like Full page zooming, Screen shots, scrolling.Media Player is the second Qt based application capable of reading most audio formats. It will have rich features like capability of saving playlists which will be implemented.Further, one of the applications based on Qt will be ported on Nokia’s popular ‘S60 version5’ mobile based platform using Carbide.C++ interface.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-084</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>IMAGE PIN POINTER</Project_Name>
	<Domain>USER APPLICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Image Pin Pointer” software aims at correlating the GPS and Camera data. Once the data is correlated, Geo-location is used to pin the image on Google maps for visual inspection.“Image Pin Pointer” will optionally archive the images and associated data to permanent storage in the database. This data will be used to plot the distribution of specific species.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-086</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>BE INFORMED (SMS BASED SYSTEM)</Project_Name>
	<Domain>USER APPLICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>In any community there is a need of proper management of    the information of all the members. Also there is a need of an efficient mechanism by which notifications regarding the events organized in the community, activities carried out by the community and general messages can be sent to the members irrespective of their physical location. Also a provision is required by which members can obtain the contact details of other members of the community. Thus this system is developed in which all the information of the members can be stored. SMS service is used for enquiring the contact details and also for sending notifications. This service can be used only by the registered members.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-175</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>REMOTE INSTALLATION OF SOFTWARE AND LAN SEARCHING USING MOBILE AGENT</Project_Name>
	<Domain>USER APPLICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>In this project we developed a system that performs software installation on a vast heterogeneous network using mobile agents. More specifically, the Aglets platform has been used to achieve this purpose. We require that a one time installation of the aglet server is done on all nodes in the network. When new software is to be installed, the central server is responsible to send agents over the network that performs the installation. Error handling and security features have also been addressed in our system.A method for remote installation of software using Mobile Agents over a computer network allows a user to interactively select each remote computer system for software installation, or to provide a file containing a list of all remote computer systems.The method then combines all files that are being remotely installed into a single data stream, sends this single data stream over the network to the remote computer system, and separates the data stream into the original files on the remote system and install software automatically.Besides installation capabilities, we successfully developed another application using this agent technology, LAN Search Engine. LAN Search Engine is a utility for fast file searching across your LAN. You can search for specific file names or for specific file types (e.g. all MP3 files). LAN Search Pro offers features that allow you to perform actions on the found items (copy, move, rename etc.).</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-352</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>HIGHLIGHT AUTOMATION</Project_Name>
	<Domain>USER APPLICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>In certain applications such as telecast of highlights of a cricket match, it is necessary to select a few frames consisting of important events of a match from the full length video file that consists of the recording of the entire match. The process of selection of frames is both time consuming and tedious, if performed manually. It is therefore required to be automated.Most of the highlights at present are generated manually. Moreover a lot of time is consumed in this process.The process may become efficient, if highlight generation is carried out using an automated tool.This project aims at developing efficient software that has both manual and automatic highlight generation options. The system will automatically extract important frames and a few may be added/deleted manually. Automatic extraction may be carried out using scenechange method using histogram and audio techniques.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-454</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>BLOOD BANK A MOBILE APPLICATION</Project_Name>
	<Domain>USER APPLICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>India’s blood requirement is about six million units (1 Unit = 350 ml) per year. Blood banks are able to collect only about three million units per year. Patients actually die because the right kind of blood does not reach them in time. The heavy shortfall in supply encourages racketeering in blood and blood products. It also encourages blood donation for money, encouraging ‘professional’ donor ship. Professional donors come from weaker sections of the society and are rarely in ideal health for blood donation and do it only for commercial reasons. It is believed that if 2% of India’s population donates blood once a year, the blood requirement of the country can be easily met.The idea: To make blood donors available within few minutes for a patient.The rough structure of the project can be stated as: There will be database of people living in a particular municipal region, in the corresponding municipal office. The project will imply a SMS based application. There will be server program handling the database installed on one of the computers in the municipal office. Donors will register themselves by sending a particular typed message and server will reply for successful registration. The hospital requiring blood of particular blood group will send message regarding the requirement in particular format to the contact number issued by Municipal corporation. The server will process the message. A reply containing names of donors and their phone numbers and ids will be sent to the hospitals through reply SMS. Hospitals will contact those donors for blood. Once the hospitals gets the blood required, they will again sent a message giving the ids of the donors who will have actually donated the blood, which will be very helpful for entry modification in database. The government will issue certificates to the donors once a year according to their number of donations.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-461</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>ONLINE FORM FILLING WITH THE HELP OF SPEECH RECOGNITION SYSTEM</Project_Name>
	<Domain>USER APPLICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Now days as we know that many our Government processes are driven largely by information – from field reports and case histories to requests for services and regulatory compliance paperwork or on computer on their systems. Which is definitely an extra overhead for the typist and also novice persons which will leads the major chances of errors and less productivity for particular organization. Also for the existing systems end user must have basic knowledge of the computer.What if there is a faster, easier way to complete intensive documentation? The ability to automate repetitive or complex document creation tasks presents enormous opportunities for enhancing produc¬tivity, increasing efficiency and reducing costs.Hence this things allows us to work on it make things more accurate and as fast as in order to improve the particular organization productivity, increasing efficiency and saving lots of time. In our proposed system of Speech recognition technology will enable government agencies to dramati¬cally reduce the time it takes to create documents, navigate complex information systems, or complete any other time consuming tasks that require staff to type information into a computer. Consider how much faster organizations could cre¬ate and process reports if employees could dictate them instead of typing them. Imagine field reports – complete with accurate and detailed descriptions – cre¬ated entirely by voice in a fraction of the time.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-712</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>BUILD AND RELEASE AUTOMATION FOR STN AND STREAM PROJECTS</Project_Name>
	<Domain>USER APPLICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Build automation is the act of scripting or automating a wide variety of tasks that software developers do in their day-to-day activities including things like:1.compiling computer source code into binary code 2.packaging binary code 3.running tests 4.deployment to production systems 5.creating documentation and or release notesEarlier, developers used command line to pass a single source module to a compiler and then to a linker to create the final deployable object. However, compiling and linking many source code modules, in a particular order, using the command line process is not a reasonable solution. Therefore , some scripting languages such as make, maven, ant etc were developed which provided better alternatives in terms of  source code dependency management as well as incremental build processing. This was the beginning of Build Automation. Its primary focus was on automating the calls to the compilers and linkers. In recent years build management solutions provide pre and post build script processing and streamlining the actual compile and linker calls without much manual scripting. Such tools are useful for continuous integration builds where frequent calls to the compile process are required and incremental build processing is needed.Continuous Integration is a software development practice where members of a team integrate their work frequently, usually each person integrates at least daily - leading to multiple integrations per day .Each integration is verified by an automated build (including test) to detect integration errors as quickly as possible.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-856</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>MAP SHARING</Project_Name>
	<Domain>USER APPLICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Many a times the need arises for you to guide your friend to a location. Its easy if you are at same location, have a computer and an internet connection. But, what if you and your friend are at long distances? Dont worry! MapShare is here to help you.  Users can login into system. They have a friend list shown similar to gtalk. User can also add new friends. User can then select few online friends and click share map. Whatever the current state of the map for current user will be shown to all shared friends. Any operation that the user does will be reflected on the friend screens. The user can zoom, pan, mark points, lines and areas on the map. The operations will be reflected on friends screens using AJAX.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-020</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>APPLICATION ONLINE ACCESS (APPOX)</Project_Name>
	<Domain>SYSTEM APPLICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>To run any application we need to first download the setup file/s and then install it on the system. License costs, download and installation time costs are very high. Economically, this limits the number of applications that can be accessed on a system. In an organization, the challenges include installing the same application on multiple computers, accommodating multiple versions of the same application as well as updating application packages on multiple computers. APPOX is a technology that enables the organizations to respond to these management challenges by providing the server the capability to dynamically stream the applications to multiple clients over a network. Thus, APPOX serves the purpose of letting users(clients) use various applications without installing or downloading the respective setup file/s on their machines. By using this technology money, time and hard disk space can be saved. Unlike cloud computing, in APPOX the data to be processed is not sent to the server. As a result, the client’s data is safeguarded against hackers attacking network traffic. Usually, hackers convert trial versions of the applications into full versions through cracks, serial keys, etc. However (in APPOX), as the application is streamed to the volatile memory (RAM) of the client, this possibility of hacking gets ruled out. Our experimental results show that, on Fedora 8 APPOX can be successfully implemented for a Text Editor (MP-5), a Music Player (Rhythmbox), a Video/Music Player (Totem Player), a Graphic image editing/processing tool (GIMP) and a Pdf Reader (Document Viewer).</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-029</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>PRO-QL+A LINTING TOLL TO CHECK FOR COMPLIANCE AGAINST INDUSTRY STANDARDS</Project_Name>
	<Domain>SYSTEM APPLICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Today with the advent of science and technology, use of electronics in the automobile and aviation industry has increased tremendously. With this growth, the probability of discrepancies in the embedded source codes and software is a major area of concern. Thus, the need for a complete packaged tool to thoroughly assess and standardize these codes is impertinent.In computer programming, lint was the name originally given to a particular program that flagged some suspicious and non-portable constructs (likely to be bugs) in C language source code. The term is now applied generically to tools that flag suspicious usage in software written in any computer language. The term was derived from the name of the undesirable bits of fiber and fluff found in sheeps wool. For any product developed in a software company, a set of standards are formulated and finalized, to maintain the quality and safety aspects of the products. These standards are basically rules and regulations which a product needs to abide by, so as to maintain a uniform quality standard and also, avert any form of safety hazards. Why is standardized and error free software required? 1. To reduce the cost incurred due to callbacks pertaining to software defects. For eg: In the automobile industry when such a product reaches the market, the resources needed to replace this defective product then are tremendous. 2.The safety measures are of utmost precedence in such products as a single defect in the software, if not detected at the manufacturing level, can have a disastrous effect on life and property both. Thus, with a vision of developing an open source, efficient, customizable, user friendly and most importantly a cost effective option, this tool will make the complicated but extremely significant task of maintaining the high level of standards, as promised to the customer, an extremely easy and simplified job.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-105</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>CREDIT CARD FRAUD DETECTION USING HIDDEN MARKOV MODEL (HMM)</Project_Name>
	<Domain>SYSTEM APPLICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>A framework for credit card fraud detection using Hidden Markov Model. In this Architecture mainly models the sequence of operations in credit card transaction processing using a Hidden Markov Model (HMM) and show how it can be used for the detection of frauds.The idea behind this framework is trained with the normal behavior of a cardholder. If an incoming credit card transaction is not accepted by the trained HMM with sufficiently high probability, it is considered to be fraudulent. At the same time, There is try to ensure that genuine transactions are not rejected.The ATM simulation is done as a user interface in banking system,when user can insert a credit card this can be read by hardware RFID kit .After reading the credit card HMM algorithm check the transaction  and detect weather user is fraudulent or not .After fraud detection the system will send the message in tearms of random number on user mobile then user can enter this number on the screen and complete the transaction .An application of HMM in credit card fraud detection.,The different steps in credit card transaction processing are represented as the under lying stochastic process of an HMM. Experimental results show the performance and effectiveness of our system and demonstrate the usefulness of learning the spending profile of the cardholder.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>C0-197</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>SMART POWER GRID</Project_Name>
	<Domain>SYSTEM APPLICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>A Smart Power Grid is not a single entity but an aggregate of multiple networks, multiple power generation companies and multiple operators employing at varying levels of communication. It is an electricity network that can intelligently integrate the actions of generators and consumers connected to it, in order to efficiently deliver sustainable, economic and secure electricity supplies. It uses digital technology for two-way communication between producers and consumers.The smart power grid software is designed to centralize the control of all the electricity meters connected to it. The interfacing between the software and the meters is such that the software will automatically receive the meter readings from all the consumer meters at regular time intervals. The software is designed such that the process of noting down the meter readings, storing them into the database, bill generation and switching ON/OFF the meter will be automated. Sitting in front of the PC, one can view the supply and consumption of every consumer meter and monitor the system accordingly. The smart grid software can smartly detect the distribution losses and power theft taking place in the system. Managers could examine their systems, identify and avoid problems, and get information about blackouts in real time. It also provides the consumers greater information and choice of supply.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-407</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>IMPLEMENTATION OF TRANSCENDENT MEMORY IN LGUEST</Project_Name>
	<Domain>SYSTEM APPLICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Virtualization is a technology that lets you run multiple virtual machines on a single physical machine, by sharing the resources of that single computer across the virtual machines. While CPU, I/O devices and other resources are easily shared among the virtual machines, sharing of physical memory is much more difficult. Memory Management mechanisms such as Ballooning and Hotplug Memory are widely used in virtualization systems for efficient utilization of RAM, but digging deep, they have their own set of problems. For instance, ballooning allows one virtual machine to donate memory to another needy machine. But a guest which has donated a part of its memory may face thrashing in case of a sudden need of memory. Therefore, memory is increasingly becoming a bottleneck in virtualization. Transcendent Memory (tmem for short) is a new approach to efficiently utilize physical memory in a virtual environment. Specifically, it tackles the problem, by taking into account two classes of memory. Memory that is being “Underutilized” by a virtual machine is collected by ballooning into a central pool. “Unassigned” memory that otherwise goes waste, is also collected in this pool. This memory is then used as a second chance cache for the guest machines, thereby making efficient use of this memory. Transcendent memory also successfully solves the issues arising due to Ballooning by also providing a swap disk on the RAM by taking memory from the pool, thereby saving expensive disk I/O. We have tried to implement this technique on Lguest.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-409</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>DATA DEDUPLICATION IN EXT2 FILE SYSTEM</Project_Name>
	<Domain>SYSTEM APPLICATIONS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Certain applications can result in a set of files in which many different files have the same content. Using a traditional file system to store these files separately results in excessive use of disc and main memory file cache space. Using hard or symbolic links would eliminate the excess resource requirements but changes the semantics of having separate files.Data de-duplication is the ability to compare blocks of data being written to disk with data blocks that currently reside on that disk. When duplicate data is found, it gets replaced by pointer to original data removing or de-duplicating redundant blocks. Data de-duplication helps in protecting data better, recover lost files faster, reduce backup and recovery cost.We propose a solution to implement de-duplication in the EXT2 file system. It is a simple and easy to understand Filesystem compliant to most of the linux distributions and VFS architecture. The project aims to reduce archival and backup storage needs with performance impact.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-080</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>IN-VEHICLE NETWORKING AND CO-ORDINATING SYSTEM</Project_Name>
	<Domain>VLSI AND EMBEDDED TECHNOLOGIES</Domain>
	<Abstract>Vehicles today are using more electronics to cope with the diversifying requirements of drivers and passengers. In order for in-vehicle LAN to function as a dependable network, reliable connection and communications must be guaranteed through standardization. CAN is currently the de facto standard in automotive LAN protocols. It is widely used in the automotive field, from basic networks to power train and body systems. There is a need for communication between different ECU’s of automotives in efficient manner. Multiplexing is the way of transmitting digital signals between electronic components. Using CAN Protocol, we attempt to provide low cost efficient communication between different ECU’s found in vehicles.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-101</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>MICROCONTROLLER BASED ENERGY SAVING SYSTEM</Project_Name>
	<Domain>VLSI AND EMBEDDED TECHNOLOGIES</Domain>
	<Abstract>Now a day’s energy wastage is on large scale by various means like, in a day time street lights are on and most of energy wastage is at public places like colleges, hospitals, schools, government offices and most important reason is carelessness of human beings. Nobody cares about wastage of energy because of that we are facing power cut off problems and if we are saving some small amount of energy per day then though it is small but if we consider it globally then large amount of energy can be saved per day. This concept is called ‘ENERGY CONSUMPTION’ concept.This project provides full automation of electricity in rooms, labs etc. In this project, when person enters in a room then lights of that particular room will turn on (i.e. during night) automatically, during day time when person enters into a room then temperature of that room will noted and according to that temperature speed of Fan or A.C will be set automatically. At Evening Street light or college campus light will automatically turned on. Energy is wasted on large scale in public offices, schools, colleges. So our goal is to prevent this energy wastage by implementing this system.</Abstract>
</Project>

<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-402</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>SUPPLY INTERRUPTION ALERT SYSTEM</Project_Name>
	<Domain>VLSI AND EMBEDDED TECHNOLOGIES</Domain>
	<Abstract>We all know electricity is a means of development and progress for the nation but the same is also the reason for death of many beings. Electric lines used by MSEDCL carry high voltage ranging from 440V to 132KV. Cut-off in these lines can occur due to natural calamities, human actions or poor insulation of the lines. Such failures lead to dangerous situations. Humans or animals that come in contact with such conductors can be killed, or suffer from grievous injuries. To avoid such accidents we decided to develop the SUPPLY INTERRUPTION ALERT (SIA) SYSTEM. The main idea of the project is to detect the cut-off between electric lines. The SIA system is developed as an embedded system. The hardware part of the system consist of a microcontroller which controls GSM modem to give an alert message to the MSEDCL people about the failure as soon as cut-off occurs. After getting a message the authorized person from MSEDCL will turn-off the power in the line of fault. And the software part consists of a GUI screen used to send message to the common man that the line has broken in his area and so that one can be careful. This GUI screen can also be used to send certain other messages that the MSEDCL wants to send to common people. This system will not only detect the failure reason but also enable the MESDCL people to detect the area of fault soon and solve the issue in minimum possible time.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-408</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>VIRTUAL PROGRAMMABLE LOGIC DEVICE (VPLD)</Project_Name>
	<Domain>VLSI AND EMBEDDED TECHNOLOGIES</Domain>
	<Abstract>VPLD is a virtual IC created using computers I/O ports. Even microcontroller ports can be used as pins for the VPLD IC. It acts like a normal Programmable Logic Device. It is a TTL compatible IC and is capable of working just like any standard digital IC e.g. Logic gates, Timers, Adders, Multiplexers, Counters, Flip-Flops, Encoders, Comparators etc. The project presents an IC that can be programmed and re-programmed again and again with any desired logic. The presented IC is entirely microprocessor driven. Hence it is a TTL-compatible digital IC. As the IC can be used instead of any TTL IC and can be programmed according to any desired logic we name it Virtual-PLD.PLD is an electronic component used to build digital circuits. Unlike a logic gate, which has a fixed function, a Programmable Logic Device has an undefined function at the time of manufacture. Before the Programmable Logic Device can be used in a circuit it must be programmed. VPLD can be used to create user defined IC with their new functionality using Equation parser. VPLD can be used as an Analyzer which will be used to monitor the inputs and outputs of complex circuitries using Digital Logic Analyzer. VPLD can be used as Designer in which the user will generate their own waveforms and that can be used to drive and external circuitries.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-704</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name></Project_Name>
	<Domain>VLSI AND EMBEDDED TECHNOLOGIES</Domain>
	<Abstract>In today’s life we often heard the news of bomb blasts and fire injuries in railways, multiplexes, shopping malls, and many such public places. You might have heard of serial bomb blasts in India in Bangalore and Gujarat. Thus we need the security in military and other applications such as Museum, Shopping malls, Jewelry shops, Factory and so on. To save the human life in case of accidents during the manual detection such as Bomb blast, fire we can use a wireless robot. This project includes a robot which can be controlled by a Mobile using GSM network. Here the main aim is to design a Robot controlled through Remote Mobile using a DTMF detector IC. This technology domain removes the human errors and integrates the entire workflow of design organization offering features beyond regular limits increasing emphasis on security. It’s a precise security measure which detects underground metals. It also detects fire in remote areas where manpower easily can’t reach as we are using CCTV camera as eye of the robot. It notifies building occupants to take evasive action to escape the dangers of a hostile fire.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-304</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>3PHASE POWER LINE MONITORING SYSTEM FOR CNC MACHINES</Project_Name>
	<Domain>INSTRUMENTATION AND CONTROL</Domain>
	<Abstract></Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-081</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>SMART ARROWS</Project_Name>
	<Domain>INSTRUMENTATION AND CONTROL</Domain>
	<Abstract>Economists usually relate the progress of a country with the number of vehicles running on the road. India is taking giant footsteps towards becoming a developed nation. Changing lifestyles, fast growing metropolitan cities and the extent of modernization is breath-taking. As it is often said every coin has two sides so is the case here, increase in the number of vehicles has brought its own set of problems. Everyone is aware of the ever increasing traffic on the road and the difficulties arising due to it. It leads to traffic-jams, accidents, chaos and confusion. It is very necessary to manage and regulate this traffic flow. It is really alarming and shocking to know that a high percentage of all the accidents occur at the traffic junction when a driver jumps a ‘Red-Light’. It is really astonishing that majority of the accidents occur due to uncontrolled driving, overtaking from the wrong side etc. etc...  Most of the accidents occur due to driver’s sheer negligence or utter disregard to authority. Thus there is a great need of a system which would regulate the traffic flow as well as monitor the violations occurred. The purpose of this system is to improve transportation operations and safety, it is vital these technologies are perceived as accurate and reliable and are applied fairly. Our project proposes an idea or methodology which will work in tandem with the existing traffic light system. Our project works as an additional regulatory system as well as will monitor the violations occurring at the traffic junction.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO=091</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>SOLAR RECORDER</Project_Name>
	<Domain>INSTRUMENTATION AND CONTROL</Domain>
	<Abstract>This project works on solar radiation measurement with microcontroller .Solar radiation in large form in nature and it has many advantages and disadvantages in all living and nonliving organism. So we can detect the actual radiation following on particular area for various application purposes. In this project we used solar cell for radiation receiver. I to V converter is used of convert current into voltage. ADC used for converting analog into digital conversation. Microcontroller is used to control all hardware and process the data.  After processing data and accurate reading is available on output device. This project we measure irradiation in a day a calculate insolation falling on particular area.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-104</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>PICK AND PLACE ROBOTIC ARM</Project_Name>
	<Domain>INSTRUMENTATION AND CONTROL</Domain>
	<Abstract>We describe a mechanical agent for the localization and description of the movements of the robotic arm using microcontroller based systems for its operations. Active contour techniques are applied for interpretation of the movements processing data coming from a remote control. Now day a pick and place robotic arm perform operation base on fixed  time  interval and they perform only fix movement .  if the object  which is moving on conveyor is not  present within the time  robotic arm  miss the object  and production failure occur. Our project deals with the movement of a robotic arm both manually and automatically to handle materials and perform operations such as pick and place. first  it detect the objects  which is moving on conveyor .pick it and place at desire location. So it    The software program does the job of controlling the movement of arm by on/off control of DC geared motors.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-264</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>TURBIDITY AND pH MEASUREMENT SYSTEM</Project_Name>
	<Domain>INSTRUMENTATION AND CONTROL</Domain>
	<Abstract>Water is the ubiquitous chemical substance composed of hydrogen and oxygen. Clean, fresh drinking water is essential to human and other life forms. It functions as a solvent for a wide variety of chemical substances and facilitates industrial cooling and transportation. Approximately 70% of freshwater is consumed by agriculture. Hence to know what quality of water we use in our day to day life is very essential for us our health and every where it is used. Turbidity and pH as defined below are the most basic parameters of water that decide quality of water in most applications. This project helps us to analyze the pH and turbidity of water. Also we can control the pH as per user requirement. Thus helping us know what quality of water we are using. The pH is controlled by adding appropriate acidic or alkaline solutions into the water. The system is calibrated using international standards. pH: It is defined as the negative logarithm of the hydrogen ion concentration. It tells whether water is acidic or alkaline. pH is chemical property of water.  Turbidity: It is the amount of cloudiness in the water. In simple words it is transparency of water. It is physical and optical property of water.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-853</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>AUTOMATIC RAILWAY GATE CONTROL SYSTEM AND STATION DISPLAY IN RAILWAY</Project_Name>
	<Domain>INSTRUMENTATION AND CONTROL</Domain>
	<Abstract>Railway is lifeline of India. It travels allover in India. At many places road crossing gate exists operated by men. There are some drawbacks time, wastage of manpower in low density traffic areas so we design system which uses vibration sensor technique for operation of gate control.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-076</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>XBMC PLUGIN DEVELOPMENT FOR ONION.TV</Project_Name>
	<Domain>MULTIMEDIA</Domain>
	<Abstract>Videos comprise maximum portion of the media in markets like online education/training, news, entertainment, TV, advertisements and so on. However, most of the videos that are published today are in fact just ‘videos’ – scenes with sound. We wish to change this landscape.  We help content companies enhance these videos into rich media experience that delivers value to audience and thus get maximum returns for the content companies. The content companies can integrate relevant information with audio / video and make their media more rich and useful. XBMC is free, open source (GPL) multimedia player that runs on the first-generation Microsoft Xbox. Usually, media players can play any video present on local machine. But XBMC multimedia player enables user to watch online videos from websites like YouTube, Hulu, etc. It also provides functionality to play audio files, image browsing and weather forecasting. Media players are used to play entire video but they do not provide any idea about contents of video beforehand. This causes an overhead of searching through entire video for user’s area of interest.  Onion.tv has planned to provide this additional functionality to XBMC through its plugin. This plugin adds feature of indexing to online videos. It will enable user to browse through the video and directly find his area of interest. Thus, this plugin is providing an enhancement to normal media player.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-195</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>ADAPTIVE MUSIC MIXING AND SYNCHRONISATION</Project_Name>
	<Domain>MULTIMEDIA</Domain>
	<Abstract>In movie making , when video shooting is over the actors are called in sound studio to record their voice so as to eliminate noise present at the location of shooting .The process of adding voice track is called as “Dubbing”. After dubbing the background music is adding into sound track. However the level of music is so adjusted that when somebody is narrating a dialogue, the level of background music is drastically reduced, on the contrary when there is no dialogue in scene the background music is played on full level. This level of music is adjusted manually. Most of the sound editors presently available in market do not have facility of adaptively mixing music with voice. In many multimedia presentations when voice is delivered in background some of the pronunciations are not heard properly and it is likely that users may miss some of the important information. The best solution to overcome this problem is to provide synchronized text display which will show appropriate text matter according to narration being delivered at that moment of time. This text synchronization facility is also not available in the sound editors available in the market. Our project aims at designing and developing sound editor which will provide facility for automatically adjusting background music according to the voice level. Similarly the editor will also provide facility for synchronizing text with voice.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-351</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>A TRAINING SYSTEM FOR AN ENGINEERING GRAPHICS STUDENT USING STEREOSCOPIC VISION</Project_Name>
	<Domain>MULTIMEDIA</Domain>
	<Abstract>To understand the complex concepts in Engineering Graphics 3-Dimenional visualization is required. Since all available surfaces are 2-Dimentional i.e. computer screen and papers. Therefore teachers can’t explain c omplex 3-Dimenional concept and students can’t clear their basic concepts of orthogonal projections in engineering drawing. This project proposes a method in which a stereoscopic vision is used to view 3-Dimensional object by using a colored goggles through computer monitor. In this stereoscopic vision objects are displayed as if they are in Real world. This project is also helpful for teaching Computer Graphics, Molecular Chemistry, and Virtual Reality. In this project a user can view previously stored objects but in a different way i.e. object will be displayed as if it is floating in real world out of the screen and he can see and understand himself various views of object by rotating an object in 3Dimensional space.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-007</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>MOVEMENT RECOGNITION AND AUDIO GUIDANCE DEVICE FOR VISUALLY IMPAIRED PEOPLE</Project_Name>
	<Domain>DIGITAL SIGNAL PROCESSING / SPEECH /IMAGE PROCESSING"/></Domain>
	<Abstract>In recent years there has been an escalation, orientation and way finding technologies and systems for visually impaired people. These technological advancements, however, have not been matched by a suitable investigation of human-computer interaction (e.g. designing navigation aids for people who form different cognitive maps for navigation).Even though some of the systems are able to guide the user to their target during guidance the input from the user is not considered sufficient.  Therefore we need to establish modified and novel systems which will cater the needs of such blind people. Our system deals with the state-of-art in field of technology assistive devices for sight-handicapped people. It concentrates in particular on the use of image and video processing for converting visual data into rendering modality that will be appropriate for blind user. Such alternate modalities can be auditory, sensory or a combination of both. Our system captures image of objects moving in front of blind people and generates a suitable count in the form of an audio signal which will be audible to the blind user. Thus, the blind user will carry a camera and portable audio device which will help him to move from one place to another.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-036</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>EXEMPLAR BASED IMAGE INPAINTING</Project_Name>
	<Domain>DIGITAL SIGNAL PROCESSING / SPEECH /IMAGE PROCESSING"/></Domain>
	<Abstract>Object removal from images is an image manipulation technique. Objects are removed from digital images and the hole left behind is filled by a graphical technique called inpainting in a visually plausible way. This technique can be applied not only to images consisting of simple textures but also to real life images having complex textures and color scheme. The goal in each case is to produce a modified image in which inpainted region is merged into the image so seamlessly that typical viewer is not aware that any modification has occurred. In the past many algorithms have been proposed. They fall into following two categories:1. Texture synthesis algorithms 2.Image Inpainting algorithms The former works well for “textures” and the latter for linear “structures” which can be thought of as one dimensional patterns like lines or contours. The shortcoming of texture synthesis is that it focuses on the entire image space without giving priority to linear structures. The result will thus have distorted lines. Inpainting technique extends linear structure to the gap by utilizing isophote information of boundary pixels. Since extension uses diffusion techniques blur is introduced in the picture. Crimimisi’s algorithm combines the advantages of above mentioned approaches in an efficient manner. In order to further enhance the results we have referred to Cheng’s contribution and have used it in our algorithm. Applications in image inpainting range from removal of an object from a scene to retouching of a damaged painting or photograph.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-073</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>IMAGE BASED PATTERN RECOGNITION MODULES</Project_Name>
	<Domain>DIGITAL SIGNAL PROCESSING / SPEECH /IMAGE PROCESSING</Domain>
	<Abstract>This project is a venture in the domain of image processing and implements image based pattern recognition modules. It introduces a set of novel algorithms for: 1.Recognition of on-line alphanumeric character display using colour-based segmentation 2.Moving object detection 
 3.Vehicle identification by licence number extraction The first implementation, tracks an on-line display of alphanumeric characters, by a colour based segmentation approach.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-171</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>IRIS RECOGNITION SOFTWARE</Project_Name>
	<Domain>DIGITAL SIGNAL PROCESSING / SPEECH /IMAGE PROCESSING</Domain>
	<Abstract>A biometric system provides automatic identification of an individual based on a unique feature or characteristic possessed by the individual. Iris recognition is regarded as the most reliable and accurate biometric identification system available. Most commercial iris recognition systems use patented algorithms developed by Daughman, and these algorithms are able to produce perfect recognition rates. The iris recognition system consists of an automatic segmentation system that is able to localize the circular iris and pupil region, occluding eyelids and eyelashes, and reflections. The extracted iris region was then normalized into a rectangular block with constant dimensions to account for imaging inconsistencies. Finally, the phase data from Log-Gabor filters was extracted and quantized to four levels to encode the unique pattern of the iris into a bit-wise biometric template. The Hamming distance was employed for classification of iris templates. We completed our work on the Chinese “CUHK” data base. It is having 36 different people images with 3 images of each person i.e. total 108 images. The “FAR” (False Acceptance Ratio) is 3.32% and “FRR” (False Rejection Ratio) is 1.85%. The time required and accuracy of the process is greater than 96% as per calculation.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-242</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>DIGITAL WATERMARKING DEVICE</Project_Name>
	<Domain>DIGITAL SIGNAL PROCESSING / SPEECH /IMAGE PROCESSING</Domain>
	<Abstract>With the recent rapid growth of networked multimedia systems, digital watermarking techniques have widely been used in high security documents and for integrity checking. Digital watermarking is a technique to add hidden copyright notices or secrete messages to digital audio, video, or image forms. This project is divided into two parts. In the first part, we have embedded watermark into the image. This is nothing but an encoding of watermark. And in the second part we have designed decoder, which is used to recognize presence of watermark. The purpose of digital watermarks is to provide copyright protection for intellectual property thats in digital format. Unlike printed watermarks, which are intended to be somewhat visible, digital watermarks are designed to be completely invisible, or in the case of audio clips, inaudible. Moreover, the actual bits representing the watermark must be scattered throughout the file in such a way that they cannot be identified and manipulated. And finally, the digital watermark must be robust enough so that it can withstand normal changes to the file, such as reductions from lossy compression algorithms.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-431</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>SMART SIGNAL USING RFID TECHNIQUE AND IMAGE PROCESSING</Project_Name>
	<Domain>DIGITAL SIGNAL PROCESSING / SPEECH /IMAGE PROCESSING</Domain>
	<Abstract>The unit at signal consist of Micro Controller, LED panels, PC interface and camera, MAX232, GSM modems etc. We use Micro Controller AT 89C51 for controlling purpose. To measure the traffic density the photos (images) will be taken using camera. These images will be processed using MATLAB to find the traffic density. Corresponding information of traffic density will be send to microcontroller. By measuring the traffic density we can automatically set the timings for different signals. The unit at server contain the database of users when particular user ID is received this database will be updated and the SMS regarding “fine payment” will be send to particular user who have broken the rule.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-016</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>POWERLINE CARRIER COMMUNICATION</Project_Name>
	<Domain>COMMUNICATION SYSTEMS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Data transmission over power lines has received increasing attention in recent years. Power lines are omnipresent and have been under-utilized as a resource for transmission of voice/data.  Even in today’s world of high speed internet and fiber optics, traditional Power Line Carrier (PLC) is still widely used to provide real-time communications for protection of high voltage transmission lines. PLC is often the most economical and reliable high-speed dedicated channel available for protective relaying. In our project we are trying to deal with the “no new wires” concept of using the existing infrastructure of power line cables is emerging as an effective means to satisfy this communication need.The idea of combining communications signals and electricity on a single. Transport medium is an obvious one. With approximately 95% worldwide coverage, the electricity grid is the largest network of all.P.L.C.C implements communication links over existing power transmission networks. P.L.C.C. is a technology that utilizes electricity power lines for the transmission of process, data, and voice signals. The basic principle behind this communication technique is that the signal is modulated with a high-frequency carrier signal; then this high frequency signal is coupled to the power line for communication.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-404</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>SHORT MESSAGING SERVICE USING CODE HOPPING TECHNIQUE</Project_Name>
	<Domain>COMMUNICATION SYSTEMS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Our project is based on code hopping concept. It means the codes get rolled after each transmission. We are transmitting 8-bit data so after 256 transmissions code get repeated. We are using 89C52  microcontroller to encrypt and decrypt data.  
Code-hopping means that code contained in a transmitted message changes or ‘hops’ with every new transmission. If a transmission is sent containing for example, a control signal and then at some time later the same control message is repeated, the encoding of the second message will be different from the first, even though the control being sent is the same.            Anyone equipped with a suitable receiver can monitor and record transmissions. If the remote control in question were being used to disarm a burglar alarm system it would be unwise to use a standard fixed-code message to do this because the message could be recorded and later re-transmitted by a would-be thief, allowing them to disarm the alarm system. 	In a security orientated remote control application, correct identification of the sender is required. Preventing the “identity fraud” of the sender is the aim of the code-hopping transmitter. Encryption by itself is not useful, since encrypted signals can be recorded and re-transmitted in the same manner as non-encrypted ones. The encryption process must cause the transmitted code to change for every message, even if the message being sent is exactly the same each time, thus preserving the uniqueness of the legitimate sender.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-006</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>HIGH PERFORMANCE RAID OVER ISCSI</Project_Name>
	<Domain>DATABASE AND STORAGE</Domain>
	<Abstract>To geographically distribute data and use the redundancy in RAID to advantage over high disk load to increase read performance The project aims to create a storage environment in which remote disks are accessed and RAID is implemented over them increase the performance of the RAID by dynamically selecting such a subset of disks so as to get highest read performance. Today, the size of the data has become very huge. The data being an important entity, no organization can afford to lose it. Rather than keeping entire data at a single location, data is being distributed over multiple locations. It facilitates easy management and security. Hence, distributed systems are being used widely. Distributed system essentially involves use of network. Whenever any network is involved, delay involved data transactions are to be taken into consideration. So it is important to achieve efficiency of transfer over the network.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-064</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>WATERMRKING RELATIONAL DATABASES</Project_Name>
	<Domain>DATABASE AND STORAGE</Domain>
	<Abstract>We present an effective watermarking technique geared for relational data to preserve ownership of database. This technique ensures that some bit positions of some of the attributes of some of the tuples contain specific values. The tuples, attributes within a tuple, bit positions in an attribute, and specific bit values are all algorithmically determined under the control of a private key known only to the owner of the data. This bit pattern constitutes the watermark.Only if one has access to the private key can the watermark be detected with high probability. Detecting the watermark neither requires access to neither the original data nor the watermark. The watermark can be detected even in a small subset of a watermarked relation as long as the sample contains some of the marks. A watermark can be applied to any database relation having attributes which are such that changes in a few of their values do not affect the applications.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-265</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>ELECTRONIC TOLL COLLECTION USING RFID</Project_Name>
	<Domain>DATABASE AND STORAGE</Domain>
	<Abstract>Transportation sector is one of the important one which contributes a lot to the development of the country. For faster and smooth transportation, the government is enhancing the quality of roads. For better facilities one has to pay price and toll tax is that price. This project displays electronic collection of toll taxes with AVI technology using RFID. Our system will sense the vehicle, automatically deduct the amount and display remaining balance on LCD. Facilities like anti-theft, account creation, deletion and balance recharge are also provided.The objective of our project is to create an integrated system for electronic toll collection using RFID. This project displays electronic collection of toll taxes with AVI (Automated vehicle classification) technology using RFID. Our system will sense the vehicle, automatically deduct the amount and display remaining balance on LCD. By automatically identifying the vehicle no. and account no. this system saves the driver’s significant time. The user will also benefit from wait times in the check out line. Additionally, user has the benefit of seeing their account balance. Facilities like anti-theft, account creation, deletion and balance recharge are also provided.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-708</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>RESULT ANNOUNCEMENT SYSTEM</Project_Name>
	<Domain>DATABASE AND STORAGE</Domain>
	<Abstract>In today’s world everything needs to be done from the comfort of one’s home or office.For this application is prepared in such a way that they can be easily accessed through computers.In the same way our project’s aim is to provide the entire information to the user at the tip of his fingers.Due to this project the traditional manual way of handling the customers queries will be handled in a more technological and automated way.This type of system performs operations similar to that of a human telephone operator.The mentioned project is based on the world’s most powerful Intel controller 8051. Most of the services provided in today’s world are voice interactive, you call up your bank and computerized voice will speak to you, and guide you to enter a particular number from your phone to get the desired service. This service is only available through the fast speed computers and having huge amount of memory.We implemented interactive service for college applications.Now-a-days every institution needs automation. As a part of college automation, we have decided to do a project for College Automation i.e. Result Announcement System using IVR technique. Our project allows the user to know the student’s attendance and marks quickly through the telephone line without the intention of the college authority. Presentation in the class and outcome of the university are made reachable to the parents by our project. It will be very obliging to the parents to be acquainted with their son’s/daughter’s recital in the college.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-009</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>EUCALYPTUS FAULT TOLERANT ARCHITECTURE</Project_Name>
	<Domain>MIDDLEWARE AND DISTRIBUTED SYSTEMS</Domain>
	<Abstract>In this day and age, where reliability and cost effectiveness are considered to be of paramount importance, the concept of cloud computing has come as a respite for one and all. The term “Cloud Computing”, refers to the users being able to use the software and data stored on remote systems owned by the cloud service providers, instead of being confined to using just their own. Private cloud and internal cloud are neologisms that some vendors have recently used to describe offerings that emulate cloud computing on private networks. EUCALYPTUS (Elastic Utility Computing Architecture Linking Your Programs To Useful Systems) is an open-source private cloud platform (http://open.eucalyptus.com) that will provide various people in the field of academics an opportunity to study and research upon the emerging field of Cloud Computing. But the Eucalyptus private cloud has a master-slave kind of architecture. It consists of 3 main components: Cloud controller, Cluster controller, Node controller. And if any one of these components fails, then the entire setup can collapse. But as is the case with all data centre technologies, this needs to be made fault tolerant. Hence have built a mechanism that will make the private cloud setup tolerant from:  1. Node controller failure. 2. Cluster controller failure. And a Java based GUI for the same. Also, we have designed a Java module, which allows users to build customized Ubuntu images which can be run on the Eucalyptus private cloud setup.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-019</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>REAL TIME MONITORING OF BUSSINESS PROCESSES IN EAI</Project_Name>
	<Domain>MIDDLEWARE AND DISTRIBUTED SYSTEMS</Domain>
	<Abstract>TIBCO ActiveMatrix BusinessWorks™ is one of the leading service creation, orchestration, and integration products on the market. It has been deployed by over 1,000 companies worldwide and is the foundation for several of the largest mission critical service-oriented business applications in production today. The problem statement of the project involves monitoring BW processes and providing extended monitoring capabilities for execution of processes at runtime. The project involves use of technologies like Java, VC#, platforms like Silverlight, JMX, Axis-2.The project after completion will be integrated with the current Framework with Business Works Service Engine which will allow other Clients to use the tool over a network.At present there is no such tool available to monitor the Business Process Instances at runtime. This application provides the user with a intuitive GUI to monitor the Business Process Instance which are currently active, have been completed or terminated due to some error. The tool provides a complete stack trace of the error condition which led to the process abrupt termination. The tool also lets user understand which path/transition is followed in a particular job if there are parallel paths of execution.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-196</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>AUTOMATED WEBSITE DEPLOYMENT USING POWER SHELLS</Project_Name>
	<Domain>MIDDLEWARE AND DISTRIBUTED SYSTEMS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Everyday, we make changes to web projects, which need to be deployed to development servers, sometimes on beta servers, and finally on the production server. Using Power Shell scripting, we can automate all the manual work that we do again and again on your deployment package every time you upload your website to some server. We use this script in page flakes every single day during our local development server upload, beta release, and final production server release. The new version gets deployed within two minutes without any manual work at all, and completely removes any possibility of human error during deployment.Copying modified files, changing files names, configuring web.config, optimizing and compressing HTML and JavaScript files, zip, FTP, all are done by shell scripts. Compression of file reduces script download time significantly, and improves the overall site download speed. Same while automated the process of taking daily backup of websites.  It saves hundreds of hours of manual labor. We can prevent any human errors during deployment, and can greatly speed up day to day patch releases on production servers using these scripts.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-004</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>MULTIMEDIA APPLICATION DEVELOPMENT ON MULTICORE PLATFORM</Project_Name>
	<Domain>OTHER</Domain>
	<Abstract>Mp3 is one of the most common audio file formats in use today. The mp3 file format reduces the size of a regular audio file (PCM file) to one tenth of the original thus allowing rapid file sharing and downloading. With the advent of multicore processors, hardware level parallelisation is in place and processor speeds and capabilities have reached a new level. However, most of the code written for the commonly used applications is in serial format. Thus the applications are not able to exploit the underlying multicore architecture to the fullest. We consider one such commonly used application, the mp3 decoder and try to optimize the serial code for multi core processors. The optimization results, thus achieved, can be observed by performing performance analysis. After having implemented a parallelised decoder code, we look into the performance issues and compare and contrast the performance of the serial (non-optimized) code with that of the parallel (optimized) code for the same machine.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-027</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>SOCIAL NETWORKING BASED DOCTORS RECOMMENDATION SYSTEM</Project_Name>
	<Domain>OTHERS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Health care sector works for the benefit of society at large.The aim of this application is to make the right doctor available to its users online. Benefit to end customer (Patient):When in a need of a doctor, the usual way to find him is by a telephonic conversation. But it is not quite feasible always. One can also do it by using online facilities like Yahoo answers, Blogging, social networking sites such as Orkut, Facebook. Etc.Through options like Yahoo answers or blogging, replies are from people whom one necessarily does not know and so usually not trusted. Hence it is a normal tendency of people to visit those doctors which are recommended by their acquaintances. So using social networking sites is preferable.Social networking sites allow users to ask queries and get replies from their friends. But using this functionality our application will allow users to ask queries regarding doctors and get replies. But there are some drawbacks like: 1.If there is an overwhelming response from friends, then it becomes difficult for the user to find the most relevant replies. 2. Also one may not be able to find out which is the most recommended doctor. 3. Also, if there are no replies, then problem cannot be solved.Our application will overcome all of the above drawbacks. It will analyze all the replies and select the most relevant ones.Secondly, it will also be able to show the most recommended doctors.Thirdly, if there are no replies, then system can provide answers from existing database of responses, if there are any.So our system will remember all the recommendations made by people, tabulate them, and then allows analysis of the results which would produce very useful data.The basic motivation behind this project is to have an application which satisfies above requirements along with some more which can be identified in the due course and is easily available on commonly used social networking site.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-039</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>DYNAMIC QUEUE HANDLINGOF SCSI DEVICES</Project_Name>
	<Domain>OTHERS</Domain>
	<Abstract>This project aims to design and implement an adaptive and highly efficient algorithm to avoid the aborting of the requests coming onto the SCSI disks (target) in SAN (Storage area network). Every SCSI device has a queue to store the requests (commands) generated by initiator. When the initiator tries to simultaneously push N commands to the target, time to serve those commands, can be more than timeout for any single command. Hence one or more commands in the tail of the queue can not be served on time less than the timeout, so the initiator will decide that they are stuck on the target. And these commands are	aborted	 by target, reducing the performance	of SAN severely in seek intensive workloads. Increasing or decreasing the queue depth on the target dynamically based on how slow/fast the back storage speed is, comparing to the target link, will be the best solution to overcome above problem.  An algorithm is designed to generate some formulae to maintain the queue depth dynamically. This algorithm gives the best solution to satisfy all the commands without aborting them, hence enhancing the CPU performance and making Linux the best storage OS.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-103</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>COIN SEPARATOR USING WEIGHT SENSOR</Project_Name>
	<Domain>OTHERS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Today is the world of automation .As we see that automation is used everywhere. There are many coins being collected in temples, casino and coin banks. The main question arises that “How to sort out these coins?” It is very difficult and time consuming job. To sort coins large man power required .The pilgrim places like Shirdi and Tirupati Balaji  where coin are collected in huge amountSorting of these coins takes place by “Coin separator”. Coin separator sorts these coins on the basis of diameter. But there are lots of disadvantages of those machines.
Man power is required for operating these machines. It requires high maintenance .Operation of these machines are not  completely automatic , for operating these machines man power is required .Main disadvantage of that machine is that it is not been manufactured in India. It is imported form foreign countries like USA , UK .The cost of such machine is about 6 lacks , which is very expensive .It is not possible for the developing countries like India to afford such expensive machine for limited applications.Its maintenance cost is also very high .It sorts the coins on the basis of diameter so that it unable to sort new and old coins of 1rupee or any other coin.Considering the economic factor involved in opting for the above systems a more provident system has been designed which can very be used for both commercial and domestic purposes. It is quite easy to install and operate and their number of complications involved is also reduced.We are designing “Coin separator using weight sensor” machine. Which sort out the coins on the basis of their weights? For sensing the different types of coin we are using weight sensor .In our project we are sorting three types of coins. Mechanical assembly is used for coin dropping mechanism. It contains two mechanisms: Arm mechanism and coin dropping mechanism.DC motors are used for coin dropping mechanism .These DC motors are derived by driver circuits. The weight of   each coin is saved in database using lookup table in the microcontroller. According to that microcontroller gives the instructions to driver circuit to drive the DC motors. In this way different coins are collected in respective boxes.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-194</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>PLUG-IN DEVELOPMENTFOR TRAC TO DISPLAY A GRANTT CHART</Project_Name>
	<Domain>OTHERS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Trac is an open source web-based software project management and bug/issue tracking system emphasizing ease of use and low ceremony. It provides an integrated Wiki, an interface to version control systems, and a number convenient ways to stay on top of events and changes within a project. Trac uses a minimalistic approach to web-based software project management. Trac helps developers write great software while staying out of the way.Trac has various plug-ins such as Timeline, Tickets, Roadmap, etc.A timeline shows all current and past project events in order, making the acquisition of an overview of the project and tracking progress very easy. The roadmap shows the road ahead, listing the upcoming milestones. Ticket system has been designed with the goal of making user contribution and participation as simple as possible. The Trac ticket database provides simple but effective tracking of issues and bugs within a project. Tickets are used for project tasks, feature requests, bug reports and software support issues.A Gantt chart is a graphical representation of the duration of tasks against the progression of time. Gantt charts are very useful for planning a scheduling a project based on different tasks that will need to be completed and their durations and dependencies on other tasks.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-243</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>BRAILLE PRINTER</Project_Name>
	<Domain>OTHERS</Domain>
	<Abstract>The blind, despite of having the strong desire to learn, earn and make a stand in the society, they are unable to do so just because they are deprived of vision.our project braille printer proves to be a helping hand to fulfill their dreams and desires. Braille printer is necessarily an impact printer which will print the document in the braille format. Braille involves method of recognizing characters with the help of six dots arranged in 3 rows and 2 columns. Each dot is either elevated or depressed. To read, blind people then sense these elevations and depressions brought about by embossing by moving their hand over the paper. We have used electromechanical relays in order to convert the binary data bits received as electrical signals into corresponding mechanical movements of the plunges to obtain the desired embossing. Our braille printer is different than those that are already available in the market in the sense - instead of using the laser techniques to emboss the paper, we have chosen to mechanically emboss it with the help of sharp movement of needle like stainless steel plunges that are operated with the help of electromechanical relays at a very low voltage of 6v.	Designing a braille printer like we have designed is essentially a cost effective solution and would help the blind institutes in rural and sub-urban areas of india and across the globe to publish their own magazines, books etc in braille format.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-511</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>VERTICAL SEARCH ENGINE FOR JOB SEARCH USING HADOOP FRAMEWORK</Project_Name>
	<Domain>OTHERS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Vertical Search Engine for Job Search using Hadoop framework” concentrates on the field of parallel computing and information retrieval and demonstrates the use of Hadoop in implementing complex processing tasks typical for a search engine. It also uses Apache Nutch and ‘General Architecture for Text Engineering’ (GATE).The objective of this project is to extract relevant and accurate domain knowledge from the massive and intractable “digital universe”, growing rapidly, according to the search string. Generic search engines suffer from "disambiguation" or "not knowing the context”. Our system addresses this problem by allowing the custom design for job search, selecting company web sites as seed sites and thus effectively catering to the needs of the user. The targeted search creates specific and detailed information.Nutch tools like crawler, parsers for HTML and other document formats make use of Hadoop’s mapreduce paradigm. The concrete data processing in this task succinctly identifies Hadoop’s strengths as a parallel data processing engine. Map-sort-reduce primitives are used to select urls eligible for fetching, and to extract relevant information from the HTML pages, while the fetcher uses multithreading and mapreduce to minimize the time it takes to crawl. Structured and unambiguous data in fixed format from originally unstructured web pages is obtained using the GATE tool. The Hadoop distributed file system inspired by Google’s GFS can solve the storage needs for the very large files generated as a part of the web crawl. Thus, the search engine with Hadoop at its core gives excellent results.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-512</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>REPORT AUTOMATION SYSTEM FOR A CALL CENTER</Project_Name>
	<Domain>OTHERS</Domain>
	<Abstract>A BPO has several call centers at different locations and the agents do telemarketing everyday. Every group of agents has a team leader. At the end of each day, team leaders send daily sales and dialing hours report to the administrator at the main office. These reports are excel sheets which are generated by a dialer. Dialer is hardware - software device which stores all the data of agents. At the main BPO, manpower is required to combine these different excel sheets from different locations to make a consolidated report and then send it to client. Its a tedious task and very time consuming and there is possibility of making mistakes. So, major motivation of developing this web based application is to reduce monetary expenses involved and to save time.Now, our proposed system will have facility for team leaders to get logged in the site and upload excel sheets there. Then the site will automatically upload this data in database. Then according to predefined time given by the client a consolidated report will get generated automatically and will be transferred to client’s server automatically. At the same time the site will mail transfer details to the client. System will have role based access security Login is categorized as Administrator, Team leader, HR, Agent and Client.  System has facility to manage internal communication through internal mailing system. Client can view report in different formats like document and excel. This system contains three applications-web application, windows services and WCF application.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-703</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name></Project_Name>
	<Domain>OTHERS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Domain knowledge edge is crucially important in the requirements definition. Requirement analysts are not necessarily domain experts and domain knowledge in an organization is not easily visible and accessible to them. The increasing complexities of software requirements coupled with pressures to reduce time to market have  underlined the necessity for a structured mechanism to help the requirement analyst ‘jump-start’ projects (re)using  domain knowledge.Most Requirements Engineering (RE) methods treat the requirements engineering exercise as something that begins from nothing and assume a ‘clean slate’ approach which outlines a series of steps to define, analyze, specify and validate requirements collaboratively with relevant stakeholders. This project proposes a method and framework to enable Knowledge assisted Requirements Evolution (K-RE). K-RE starts with a seed requirement specification. The seed contains structured domain knowledge as represented by core elements such as business events, actions and decisions (as captured in business processes), constraints, and analysis patterns derived from various resources. Each time a new software application is to be developed; we start with this seed specification and ‘evolve’ it by way of altering and/or adding to the core to get to the final requirement specification. This is done in a semantically assisted way. The semantic assistance comes from ontologies that can be created, maintained and evolved collaboratively and a context-sensitive alert mechanism that provides online alerts as a requirement analyst evolves his/her specification from the seed. Each new exercise of requirements definition thus, becomes an evolution of a pre-existing structured domain knowledge base tailored to suit specific projects.</Abstract>
</Project>
<Project>
	<Project_ID>CO-851</Project_ID>
 	<Project_Name>ONLINE WEED AND PEST CONTROL SYSTEM</Project_Name>
	<Domain>OTHERS</Domain>
	<Abstract>Today methods of applying agents are characterized by using liquids with water as carrier for distribution on the plot. The liquid is mixed with one or more agents in the required mixture with a constant concentration and distributed by nozzles on the target area. Precision plant protection requires a higher consideration of occurrence of weeds in the plots to apply specific agents on weed locations. Directly injecting agents into the carrier means adding the agent into the outgoing water flow. Different systems have already been launched and are being used in agriculture in a few cases. Characteristic for these systems is the injection of agents in the tube system before the sprayer boom. The main disadvantage is a high reaction times until the required metering is adjusted. The project aims at the development of a system with injection of agents in the nozzle which promises less reaction time and thus higher accuracy in spot application. The entire system will rest upon sensor systems for online detection of weeds or mapping of weeds .</Abstract>
</Project>
</Student>